Alright, welcome back everyone to the qualified podcast with me today is Todd and Kristin from the Valley Clean Team. Guys, how are you today?
You're pretty good. I've got a bit of a call, so.
Alright, hanging in there. Appreciate the time and being here with us today. Absolutely.
Can you go ahead and give us a little background on yourselves? Where were you born? Where did you guys grow up?
Well, we're Alabama born and bred. I'm from the Scholes area, Muscle Shoals, Tuscumbia, or the Tennessee River in northwest Alabama.
I grew up in Decatur, Alabama, which is about an hour east of where she is.
And my father moved there for, we were at a job at TBA, so that's where we ended up working for TBA, and Decatur. So, after that we moved around and did some stuff.
I'm sure we'll get into, but yeah, that's absolutely excellent.
What's the best, best thing about where you guys live, in your opinion?
Well, we've lived all over the United States, big metro areas like Atlanta, Las Vegas, we live a little while, we live in Washington State, and of course in a couple of different places here in North Alabama.
The thing that we love about the Scholes area is it is a smaller town, but we're very centrally located to the entire like Huntsville metro area, or just a couple hours from Nashville.
About a couple hours from Memphis, a little bit short of two hours, to Birmingham, four hours to Atlanta. So, we're very centrally located, and it's just got that small town feel and a lot of history, a lot of music history.
And so, yeah, that's one of the things we really enjoy about it.
I like that it is, you know, cuts two seasons, just, you know, kind of hot and cold.
And then tornado season.
And so that's fun.
We lived, as Kristin mentioned, we lived all over the country, and, you know, different places and different vibes.
Here, it's just very relaxed.
And there's also, there's always just a good atmosphere for college football.
So that's a great one. We didn't always have that where we lived.
So.
Definitely love seeing different college football games and, and depending on what game is on, and with the home team is, you could definitely see massive school spirit and.
Oh, yeah.
You got to love it. I mean, more so than some professional sports teams, which is.
Yeah.
And we're, we're, what we consider a mixed marriage in Alabama. He is an Alabama guy and I'm an Auburn girl. So somehow we've managed.
Well, you kind of mentioned that the two seasons hot, cold and, and tornado in Chicago, it's hot, cold and construction.
So we get construction all year round.
Yeah.
One of my favorite questions to ask is when you were younger.
What did you know what you wanted to be when you grew up? Did you want to be business owners? Did.
Do you need something else?
Well, I always wanted to be a physician of some kind.
I started out probably, you know, to the normal little girl things of pediatrician.
Veterinary and stuff like that.
I actually did pursue the pediatrician kind of thing up until I hit chemistry in college. And then I said, maybe I should stick with them talents that I actually have, which had always been writing.
But I was very pragmatic and I was like, I can't be a, you know, a fiction writer or something like that.
So take this introductory to public relations class and found that writing press releases and stories about people and more like in the journalism kind of feature writing type situation was kind of where I enjoyed that.
And then one thing led to another and as you do, you end up in marketing.
And that's kind of where my career has been had been for the last 15 years or so.
Excellent.
For me, I want to be a corporate trainer.
So my, you know, kid vision after meeting a few people who worked in that space where they would, you know, do team building and, you know, trust falls and things like that.
It was strange.
So I wanted to educate and train people from a corporate standpoint, because, you know, teamwork makes the dream work, but if you don't have teamwork, then you just got a lot of disarray and HR issues.
So definitely different answer that I've ever heard for being younger corporate trainer, but it's.
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, you can get into like to the, you know, I'll astronaut, you know, things when you're a little little, but like, you know, you're 16, 17, you know, what do you want to do.
And you look at the adults around you.
You know, my, I do come from a family of entrepreneurs we both do, but we, I guess never considered it, you know, that young for ourselves.
We're always chasing, you know, a different American dream, if you will.
Yeah.
In fact, we probably were discouraged from being an entrepreneur just because of.
How hard it is.
You know, and it's like, well, if you work for someone else, do it, you know, so.
Yeah.
Now we know that.
Now we know that's not exactly true.
Then there's anybody in your family business owners, anybody you could have piggybacked off of, then teach you things or was it more just.
Do something else.
Yeah, it was, it was always do something else for us.
You know, like even the business owners that, you know, that were family members like my grandfather owned a tire store from like.
Still there today from 1946 when he opened it.
And, you know, he was always just like go to college, get a degree, you know, et cetera, et cetera.
He never, he was never like income work for me, you know, he was never.
You know, having you come over to burn the midnight old doing, you know, payroll.
So it wasn't discouraged.
It wasn't really just talked about, you know, it was more like, Hey, go, go have something safe and secure versus take a risk and.
Figure it out. So.
So we've, we've done both and we like, we like controlling our own destiny a whole lot more than then leading it up to.
Being a number of operation. Yeah, absolutely. And that.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
I was just going to say in my, my family history is, you know, just kind of blue collar workers and hardworking people.
And, you know, I had an aunt and uncle that my uncle was architect.
He owned his own architecture firm and I saw how hard he worked.
And then also all the responsibilities that came with that.
But then also like my mother, she owned a small business and she's always been.
You know, kind of a hustler and like, you know, I'm going to.
This is the next big, you know, not next big thing, but like I'm going to, you know, do this thing and she's always been successful and relatively successful and what she was doing, whether it's sewing.
She's to make handbags and she can go around to all the different.
Festivals and all of that. She kind of did the house.
Home party, ladies party booking and ordering kind of before that was a thing, you know, I think Tupperware parties, but there's.
And so she was, she's always been very entrepreneurial.
And then the last recently retired, but the last.
Probably 10 to 15 years. She started and kind of grew her own.
She's like, oh, just take a new alterations, but she's really a very talented tailor.
And she can pretty much take apart any.
Put her wedding gown and put it back together to fit the bride in a way that you would never know that it happened.
So she did that for many years out of my parents basement in town and she was very well known in the area.
And so I just saw a lot of hard, hard work and grind to be a business owner.
And while I was not opposed to that, it quite taught. It was just kind of like education was very important.
You know, go to school, get an education, get a degree course. I'm 40. And so I'm a little bit before kind of the.
When the talk of kind of popular society is today, that whole like, do we go get a formal education? Do we learn skills? You know, that sort of thing.
So back back in my day.
You know, it was, it was still go to school, get an education, get a degree and go work for somebody else.
And so, and like that's kind of background on that.
I'll be 30 in May. So I feel like I'm the tail tail end of that being like, all right.
Still go to college, but it started to teeter on maybe trade school, maybe something else, maybe entrepreneurship.
And it Todd, like you said with with your grandfather, super nice that, you know, he still pushed you to continue your education, but didn't force you to come into the family business and be like, all right, you're going to go get your education and something specific.
But you're going to come back and bring it in. And it's going to be kind of.
If you didn't know that you go back to work for us, that didn't happen luckily. So yeah.
But you know, when I was, to be honest with you with the year I was born, he actually sold it. So he retired in like 1976, which was your.
Oh my gosh.
And sold it to one of his lead sales guys who basically helped him build it so that the running joke was like I helped you build this and you're going to sell it to me for not for what, you know, just, you know, I'm building something I want to buy back from my from you later.
And I was like, yeah, you did so.
Hard work and I'll take over.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's, it's a well known cough, you know, but it still bears the Fredericks and name.
So I go by today.
Yeah.
They still on it.
So the walking.
I remember this when I was a kid, I'd walk in the front door and they would say, Mr. Fredericks and, and like the whole, like all the customers and stuff that would turn around and look.
And I, you know, feel super embarrassed. And I would say, yes, I'm here for my role.
He's check. And then they would just the owner would turn around and like walk away.
So just just to mess with him.
Sports.
Yeah.
I was like, you're going to embarrass me.
I'm going to get you back.
So.
Nice.
It's interesting now that.
With social media.
You to tick tock.
Are.
Kids growing up are going to potentially do interviews.
Maybe.
And then they're going to be possibly asked.
You know, your parents, they were business owners.
And, and kind of give these answers and then maybe their kids will carry on.
And then their response will be like, well.
My mom or my dad blew up on, on tick tock or on, on YouTube playing video games.
And it's like the, it's just so crazy how the last 30 years in technology has changed so much and how businesses.
Streamline things.
And opportunities are endless.
Everywhere.
And as long as you have creativity or the ability to put.
Processes and things together, you can, you, there's, there's really nothing you can't do.
One hundred percent.
Absolutely.
Background.
You talked on going to college.
You went to Alabama and you went to Auburn or is those are just your preferred.
Kind of like a state religion.
I have to choose one.
When you're born.
Yeah, you're born.
So.
That's true.
No, I actually went to graduated from the University of North Alabama.
Which is in the Florence area or is in Florence, which is in the shoulder area.
I went there.
When I went, it had definitely transformed.
I think they just recently got into like the vision one.
It was like a vision to school for a long time.
It has become a lovely campus.
But I went there.
When I went, we jokingly called it 13th grade because it was a local university to our high school.
And so everybody wanted to go off and, you know, go somewhere else.
And I didn't do that.
I wanted to go to Auburn.
I was accepted into Auburn and just.
I was only 17 when I graduated high school.
So I would just felt I just wasn't quite ready to go off away from home yet.
And so I stayed lived at home, went to school for a year and a half.
I was a freshman in high school when 9-11 happened.
And so went through that whole day and the whole rest of that year.
It was very difficult just growing up and being a young adult in that environment of, you know, it was really the first time that my generation had experienced anything so kind of traumatic and as a nation and that sort of thing.
And I say all that to say that after about a year and a half at UNA, I changed my thoughts on staying at home and doing finishing out at UNA and I actually transferred up to Virginia and went to school at Liberty University for a year.
And it was a good change of pace for me.
And then came back and finished up at UNA and went on from there.
For me, I got out of high school.
I had a choral music scholarship.
So I would sing and I didn't go to class because I was immature and I lost that scholarship.
And my dad said, you can go to the military or you can live in a box, you choose.
So I went to the Air Force was in the National Guard reserve component of the Air Force spent 10 years in that.
Got out 10 years.
Went to a method of school who offered me a choral music scholarship.
And then transferred from there to MTSU, Kansas State University, where I spent a couple of years, did not graduate.
Went to go work for Comcast made a lot of money and just said, I don't need that.
So, well, thank you for your service first of all.
Yes, thank you. Thank you again for your service.
Anybody who donates their time into the military is huge. So I know everybody appreciates that.
And, and, and I can relate to not going to class.
Done that a time or two. Definitely kicked me in the butt.
Graduated high school by a hair on time missed summer school, which is fantastic.
Are the community college I went to for the first two years, it was like Kristen, you said 13th grade for you.
It was our high school name 2.0.
Really no change, not much of a change at all. So it's funny how similar these things are across the country.
No matter if you're in a big city or a small town, it's, it's all kind of close.
Going towards the business now.
When did you guys first start?
The Valley Clean team in November of last year. So 2022.
So a year in.
Yes, we're a year and 28 days out.
Why did you start?
That's a fun story.
Yeah, so I have always worked for other people and I've always built businesses for other people.
So, you know, when we moved across the country and went from Alabama to Washington state or Washington state to Atlanta or Atlanta to Vegas.
It was always to, for me anyway, to grow and scale a business either need help to is, you know, lose $400,000 a year and didn't have processes and systems in place and employees kind of ran a rough shot over the ownership.
Or to go and start from start fresh like I did in Atlanta and bring knowledge to that so.
After doing those things, COVID hit.
Entire, you know, company got shut down. So the ownership who just kind of ran on the skeleton crew and didn't live in a painting executives to hang our solar house at the, at the height of, you know, just property values in the area and moved out to family land.
And I walked at the back door and slipped down a ramp and broke my leg.
Like, like, like, like, airlifted, airlifted brick.
It was fun.
I didn't feel anything, but yeah, it was opposite fun.
Wow.
So, you know, I'd always build business for the businesses for other people.
So I could not walk or put any weight on that leg for five months.
So I was.
No weight bearing.
Yeah.
For five months.
So I had a lot of like, you know, elderly DME equipment that I wouldn't, you know, have, you know, in the 40s, generally speaking, you know, around. So I had this little scooters and walkers and stuff. It was super interesting.
Anyway, so I was sitting down and, you know, watching YouTube or something.
I think it was YouTube and I ran across and it was my name of Cody Sanchez.
And Cody, it's a woman.
C.O.D.I.E. has this philosophy about buying, wearing businesses.
And I thought, well, that seems pretty simple.
I could do that.
So I started researching how to make that happen and what kind of business we'd like to either open or purchase.
From the content that she had created and the ideas that I got from that, because all I had was time off the hands and I remoted my.
But I couldn't walk, but I could use my brain.
And so we began doing business consulting, you know, and then started the Valley Clean team.
Just a couple months later.
Yeah.
And to tag on to that part, we have been married about.
Eleven years at that point.
And in 2021, at the end of 2021, we had a baby.
And so I was, I was working, like I said, my, my whole background is in corporate marketing.
I was working for a large local credit union at the time in doing marketing and project management.
I loved my job, loved, loved what I was doing.
And we were very successful in what we were doing there at the time.
And he had his accident.
We had a 10 month old.
And so that was in August of that year and of 2022 rather.
And then in October of 2022, I was unceremoniously laid off.
We were tired.
Well, yes, I was told to that I retired me and actually are one of our executive leaders in that department.
It was a shock to everybody.
I mean, it was the entire credit union.
Like I had people emailing me just like, what happened?
And it was just a restructuring.
There was nothing in a various or anything like that.
But it, no one knew it was coming, unfortunately.
And so I literally came home that day with a severance package and Tom on my hands.
And that's what I had got this great idea.
Yeah.
And he had been telling me, you know, kind of like, Hey, you've been thinking about this and that.
And I just couldn't even between the new baby working his accident and with him not being, you know, being immobile.
You know, there was just a lot on me as mom and wife and current, that current provider for the home.
And I was just like, I can't put anything else on my plate. You know, I can't, and I can't give you any of the knowledge in my head from a marketing perspective.
I just can't do it.
No, we were at the doctor's office, like, you know, brainstorming on, you know, names of the company.
Yeah.
And that's literally like, that's literally the only time that I had to focus on this idea that he had.
And we'd always talked about having our own company, you know, running our own business.
We just can never get out of the comfort, you know, of that.
Well, we always thought you had to like, Oh, I'm gonna go to the bank and borrow.
Yeah.
You know, that kind of stuff. And it's not true. You don't have to do it that way.
Sure.
Yeah. So I literally came home on that October day and I said, well, I guess I'm your school time now. And so that's.
Great. We need a logo. Let's go.
Yeah.
Couple weeks later, I think we officially worked and we had our first customer in January, December, December of 2022. So that's what we've been doing.
So I take all the operational knowledge and things that I did over the over the years as it, you know, an executive leadership and.
Just books you read and, and, you know, process and things you put together and just, you know, and then basically.
I was like, Oh, yeah, I know how to do that. I know how to set up, you know, okay, ours and, you know, smart goals and stuff. So let's just.
Do that for our business and the people who work here.
You're the first person I've ever heard that you were handed a surprise retirement in that in those terms in those terms.
Wow. It's.
That's a lot of things that you guys have went through in a very short amount of time and it just goes to show your resiliency.
All that you've gone through and where you're at now is, is.
It's just a testament to how strong you guys are and what you can accomplish with.
A little bit of brain power will and somebody strong by your side.
There's a lot of prayer in there too, because we were.
Absolutely.
I'll fall on a part, you know, just, you know, whether we don't find it or not, or we even realize it.
Frankly, so it's a sure.
It is very interesting and there's a blessing.
So how much did you guys.
What was that?
The blessings are, I mean, it's all blessings, even, you know, what will be considered bad.
Like it, but it's still good.
So how much did you guys end up investing in the business when you first started?
Less than five grand.
Very little.
Yeah.
We didn't have it to invest between, you know, his accident, you know, the move.
I mean, we literally had just sold our house and set up a new home on Raw land.
And so, I mean, we had just moved into our new home.
Two weeks before he had his accident.
Two weeks.
So we started boxes.
We had a friend come and like help us, like, just put things on a shelf because we couldn't
do it.
I mean, we just couldn't do it.
I was like, Hey, I need that over there.
He would literally sit in his, like, in a chair and just be like, can you move that there?
You know, and at the time for the first, you know, two months or whatever, you know, I was
still working.
So we've said maybe off, thank God we live literally next door to my parents.
My, a brother, a sister law and a grandparents that we moved to family land.
And I don't, I mean, without family support and just up there, Tom and energy.
I mean, dad, every week would come get our garbage can and take it down to the road and
needed that for all of a sudden.
I did.
Come check on me.
Yeah.
Bring me, you know, during the week.
The grandmother would bring him with, would have him bring me snacks.
Yeah.
She does that for everybody.
And then my, you know, my grandfather on her side would, and he's like 90 and he just, you
don't need anything, Todd.
He would just be great about it.
You know, just just Tom and they live right over there.
So, you know, they're having a real close family.
That close was very helpful.
Yeah.
But we didn't have any, I mean, we didn't have any extra cash.
We didn't have anything.
We could not.
We weren't going to the, to the bank to get a loan.
We weren't going anywhere to do anything.
We had internet.
We had our brains and we had Tom and I have to.
I mean, we were just in a position where we had to.
Yeah.
So we incorporated and did everything that we could.
You know, the cheapest way possible.
And then figure the rest out, you know, through, you know, looking at industry
professionals and what they were doing to, to run their businesses or start their
businesses and make sure we had all the systems in place.
What did the money go towards?
They went toward.
Registering the company following, you know, all the different LLCs.
It went toward.
Brand development software.
We started with a program called HSA home service academy by Johnny and Sergio.
Yep.
That's where we got a lot of the information from to kind of do everything.
So majority went there.
And then the rest of it was just like starting up this and setting up, you know.
By the domain.
Yeah.
Open phone account.
You know, what are the case may be to get all the tech working and then from
there it was, you know, finding people who wanted to work and work with us and
believed in our vision.
Yeah.
I've explained it to him, obviously.
Right.
Yeah.
I know that you know, I literally, I'm not a graphic designer.
I'm more on the business marketing kind of strategy side of things.
But I just made my graph.
I mean, you know, I know what to look for.
We do have a lot of experience and we just finally had to put our experience.
To use for us.
And I mean, I use Canva and, you know, I mean, we didn't go an expensive route, you
know, for those kinds of things.
Anything, any copy that needed to be written for our website.
I wrote it, you know, the mentality that we had at that point was good enough.
And we'll fix it later, you know, and good enough is better than nothing.
Right.
And we live a lot by the build that airplane while you fly that strategy.
We've kind of had to, you know, and a lot of my corporate takeovers.
We've done or the turn around.
It's like you've got to build the boat in the middle of the, in the middle of the
stream while there's water running.
So you've still got to communicate with the board what's going on.
So they don't lose patience with you.
So.
And with my history as in both corporate marketing and as a project manager for
marketing projects and events and stuff like that, you know, I really.
You brought that part to the table and then with his.
Operational processes, you know, that's his ballgame.
So we, we talked a lot.
We were so sick of each other that I was like, I'm, I'm going to go outside with
baby.
Like, you know, because you have to.
And it's like, there's no hard time to start.
No, no, perfect time to start.
We were forced to start.
It's like having a conversation about when you want to have a kid.
So like, you know, there's no good time to have a child.
It's just.
Do it.
And you do it.
It's not figuring out.
Like, absolutely.
We'll do it.
Or whatever.
It's like, that's an excuse.
You're just scared.
Let's just pull the trigger and let's just get this party started.
And I fully, I fully believe our child.
And then also his accident.
I mean, I literally say we're Christians.
And, you know, I was like, God put you on that couch.
Because we just would not have done it.
I don't have like a, I've had to learn, you know, a lot about boundaries and setting them between like work, work like balance and stuff where, you know, over the years, I would, you know, be an account manager for a software company.
And, you know, somebody would call with some problem and maybe should have gotten the help desk, but, you know, they have my numbers.
So here we are.
And it's at a clock at night or midnight or whatever the case may be.
And I'd always answer the phone and which is great for, you know, an MDS score, but not good when you're trying to.
Sleep. So.
And same for me. I mean, prior to baby, you know, I would answer phone calls on vacation.
You know, we were just, we were just running the rat race. I mean, you know, that's just what we were doing. And we were.
You know, but, you know, after baby came along and I'm super type a, you know, I'm like, I want to do all the things.
I never noticed.
So it makes it quite interesting.
Oh, yeah.
But when baby came along.
My name is Charlotte, by the way.
Oh, I'm such a cute bow tie. She's so sweet.
Yeah, that was.
She was a female thought she's two now, so she's running all over the place.
Yeah, she's a little bigger now. Yeah. But when Charlotte came along.
I realized real quickly that, you know, the whole, you can do it all and you can have it all.
You know, it's not super true. You can do a lot of things and you can, and you can be very strong, but you only have so much bandwidth and you have to have priorities and you have to set boundaries.
With work and family and friends and yourself.
Will power can be infinite, but time is definitely not.
No. And so we both just kind of had a realization. I definitely did.
And then, you know, that, and then when he had his accident, it got real real.
And so we just, you know, we're just going to say no, you know.
Yeah, the power of no.
Yeah.
So we had many conversations of where I was saying, it's five o'clock. Like, that's, we're done for the day. We've got family things to do.
That has been both a struggle and a blessing.
Sure.
Go to go against.
There's an occasional time where I'm like, I just take five more minutes. I got to finish this last line item on this invoice.
I feel like it's okay if you're a business owner, where if you're on vacation and, you know, something urgent comes up, you've got to take care of it.
But if you're working for somebody else and you're either a C suite employee, any, any employee where you don't own the company and you're.
It's after hours where you should be with your family and spending time with them relaxing vacation, whatever.
There's no need. Somebody else can handle it. It's not life or death.
Even as a business owner, there are things that aren't life or death and can wait.
But you are more inclined because you own it and you want to grow it. And it is like a child. You want to nurture the business and you want to make sure it's successful.
The point that we learned about that is, you know, and that's completely true, but we have, you know, good people in positions.
And just because I get all the notifications because, you know, you know, info ad or whatever, you know, I get CC donut.
I know what's happening. There's a minute. I have to action it. And sure, you know, we have, you know, people that we trust to action it.
And I'll just look at the end of the report and make sure it's, you know, taken care of.
And having that.
Allocating is huge. Having people that can handle it. And then you just oversee is key.
Yeah. And if you have to have people that you trust and then, you know, delegate those low value tasks so you can focus on, you know, building what you're going to build tomorrow or expansion or scalability or whatever.
Going back, like you said, being good enough with a general blanket of everything, but hiring people who are pros in those specific things is what every business owner should be striving for.
I've had the Steve jobs model where it's just like hire people that are smarter than you are, surround your people that are smarter yourself is smarter than you are.
And I know my weaknesses and I know my strengths that I know when I can stand in my own way or hold up something because I'm being too, you know, micro on it.
So you pay people what what they're worth and what they deserve and have been help you.
That's the reason we have, you know, marketing or, or, you know, a VA or anything else.
Yeah. And I think being okay with, okay, is, is a huge part of it. You know, we get, you know, perfection, we get, yeah, and that's kind of speaks to me is, you know, we get that perfectionism spirals that I call it.
We get, you know, lost on seeing the, you know, success motivators on social media. You know, we do want to grow and we are growing, but does it have to be a 50% month over a month?
Is that one percent, you know, better every day? Is that okay? And it is. And that's the thing, you know, we would rather, you know, have quality and have in all aspects of our life rather than quantity.
Yeah. I don't have a, you know, 35 star views on Google, then 100 one star reviews. You know, it's this. Yeah.
It's like, right. No, you, you, you, you got a lot of jobs done, but then nobody wants to call you back. That's not how we operate.
No, the 1% better everyday model is exactly how I try to be. It's not leaps and bounds that.
One of the interviews I just did. You can't go from here to here. It's doesn't work. No, it is not even sustainable. It's, you know, you just need to 1% just, you know, make, make that, you know, have a switch.
Those gurus, those social media marketers that are preaching nonstop that it's just grind until you're basically dead. It's, it's not needed. There's.
Software is in place to help you. I mean, the AI is huge. Yes. And they're pushing just.
Work until you're bleeding out of every end. And it's just, it's not, it's not how life should be.
No, it's, it's not, it's not the dream that I want to live and that we want to live.
But we had to go through a lot to realize that. And, you know, that was one of the things that I wanted to make sure we touched on was like, don't wait until you're in your 40s to finally, you know, slow down and be okay with okay.
Like you can get out of high school and go to college, get in high school, go work at McDonald's, or you can get in high school and be a housekeeper and you can make as much money as you want to because you control the schedule.
You can control you or do anything else you want to in the service. It's not, it's not required like a license or certification at the particular point.
In your state. Sure. So then what is the biggest challenges you guys have faced in this last year of being business owners?
Yeah, the biggest thing is, you know, just finding enough people to do the work to the, to the level and quality we want.
We operate off of a subcontractor model. And for us, you know, we can't tell them what to do, obviously, or do anything else that would, you know, break that boundary.
But we want to find people who, who, who stand behind us with a vision who understand what we're, what we're, you know, what we're doing, who we, you know, obviously pay well, and who can complete the job and do all the tasks that are, you know, assigned to them.
Click the on the way button, just, just follow the process. And people who have experience, there's a lot with a lot of people.
I mean, I have a massive spreadsheet with people who have a plot and, you know, only a handful of them actually have any clinic experience that sort of their own house, you know.
So that's, that's one of the major challenges is, is just being able to grow and scale and find qualified cleaners that will work, you know, work with you honestly.
Yeah. So in order to solve that, that problem, we've done a couple of different things.
Number one, we have our, our VA, constantly looking out and handling, you know, tier one and I'm doing, actually, tier two interviews today for three new cleaners, our three new prospects for cleaners.
And then the thing we do, we're developing, you know, through me and a couple of other business owners, we're developing inroads and to like local community colleges and stuff like that, where people who are going through trade skills, or even like, you know, pre nursing programs and stuff.
People who'd be interested in that and then teaching them, you know, how to do those things in a constructive course manner.
So we can, you know, kind of build, give them skills that will help our business and also help them to.
And I think one of the main things to touching on the talent, you know, fancy word talent acquisition part of things, you know, it's, it's.
We really value that hands on blue collar worker like when we started this business, that was one of our core values is like we want.
These people who are coming in and doing this hard work that requires attention to detail and planning and, you know, follow through and time management and all of these very, very highly sought after skills but because they're a house cleaner.
They're not value in our society. Like, you know, and we don't just run the business. We actually do the work too. And it's not easy.
Yeah, go, go see how much it takes after you go to go clean in month 5000 square feet of a hard pine floor. I mean, it's a lot.
Yeah.
And so we wanted to make sure that kind of untraining that stigma is been part of it too is like, Hey, you can trust us. Like, when we say, you know, we're going to do this, this and this and we're going to pay you this.
A lot of times that's a foreign concept because we are not.
We do pay well and we do, you know, have a pretty.
Through onboarding and, you know, things of that nature. So it's just, it's a different culture at our company than it is at like some of the other kind of more corporate cleaning company. So.
That's good. But you both said you were, or you said that you were type A and Todd is type A as well. So you kind of butt heads. How does that play into your leadership style for for the business.
As far as leading the face of the company, that's all Todd. He, he is.
Great.
Do what?
Great face for the company.
Thank you.
Yeah.
He is definitely the face of the Valley Clean team. He does all the networking.
As far as like formal networking.
You know, I'm a mom and Charlotte is, is my number number one. And so when kind of how it works between us is, I definitely have my opinions about things, but we consult one another and then he takes our decisions out into the company.
And so I try not to be directly involved with our providers.
You know, I'm not communicating directly with our VA, but we definitely make sure that we're on the same page. Yeah.
And then he takes that into the day to day.
There's certain areas like, you know, with our marketing experience, like we have a marketing.
Contractor consultant that I've known for years. So I'll say, Hey, Crystal, it's really better if you and Kristen just talked directly, you know, please.
Yeah.
And then you all let me know what you want to do within the budgetary, you know, confined that we've already set up and then we'll say gay or nay and go for it from there.
So I take myself out of that.
Most of the time, occasionally, Crystal will call and tell me we did a veteran's giveaway for Veterans Day.
And we did something where it's like, tell us a story about, you know, a veteran, you know, and then like you can get a free cleaning.
You know, for that.
And, and because we want to honor them and to use their story to inspire people, right? And to, and to, you know, like, like people for the Vietnam War and my father was a Vietnam veteran, you know, they were spit on when they came home, for example.
So I make a point of it whenever I see somebody wanted a Vietnam veteran hat, like in Walmart or whatever to go up and say, not thank you for your service or anything like that.
You're welcome home. And that's something that they're just like, they didn't get.
So it's fun.
So we enjoyed that part of it.
But we handle, that's how we run the business together and I give her reports and, you know, if I don't see a way to do something or if I say, okay, well, this is, you know, how we can resolve this issue with, you know, feedback from a client or where the case may be, I'll just bounce it off her and say, you know, do you see
anything else that I'm not seeing here, or some other way to solve this that, you know, that would be better overall than what I'm looking at.
Yeah. And sometimes he's just talking about something. I'm like, Hey, did you think about it this way? You know, I'm definitely, you know, we just have conversations. I mean, we just, you know, we're constantly thinking
about the business, even though we're not constantly physically working in the business, if that makes sense. So talk about it.
Yep. There's plenty of, you know, there's plenty of business owners that are sold by themselves, don't want to partner because they see they can make the decision and just go from there, don't need to consult, which is fine. If it works for them.
Great. But having a partner, not only do you separate tasks, everybody, you each do what you're good at, but like you just said, you have that partner to talk to and see, Hey, I'm, I've been sitting at this for a couple hours like, what am I missing here?
Having that second set of eyes to come in and help you out is huge and helps get that success going more. And it's great to show and grow that business with a business partner, especially if it's your spouse.
Well, one of the things that I learned, there's, there's a book called multipliers by Liz Wiseman. Never this book. Eight years ago. Yeah, eight years ago. We were as a, as a, I was a CEO of a consulting company and we consulted in the long term care space.
I went from, you know, senior account manager, software company to CEO of a consulting company in the same industry. And I had no clue what I was doing. Zero clues.
But the owner had faith that I would figure it out and, you know, turn their negative $400,000 loss they had last year and something positive.
Just with the ideas and things that I had. So one of the books I read was, you know, Liz Wiseman's book.
And you're basically getting people in the room and they talk about like Mitt Romney or talk about, you know, other people and they say there's empire builders and then there's multipliers. So you're multiplying intelligence.
I had more brains in the room as long as you're structuring that meeting correctly, but you're getting people's input. So, you know, it's always great to have more people working on a problem and balancing that with, you know, how many dollars per hour you're burning in that meeting.
That's, that's huge finding coming into something that you don't think you can handle. Like you said, you had no, no grasp of doing that.
First time in and, and taking on that challenge, because somebody backed you and said, I have the faith in you is, is huge. And that's what you guys did with the business when all those hard times fell on you at once you looked at each other and were like, I have faith in you, you have faith in me.
We got this, we're going to do it and we're going to kill it. And we got into it. It's like, well, we're going to build this for all for ourselves, but also build it for all the people who were at, you know, our competitors making 10 bucks an hour.
That's not, it's worth more than that.
Yeah, for sure. So how do you foster a positive company culture within the business?
So, for me, it's through transparency, honestly. So I am transparent with our VA and transparent with our providers. And, you know, we will just honestly have conversations.
So, you know, we mentioned it before about, you know, just how we structure things and some of our went and really gotten into our OKRs and goal setting and stuff, but we do everything together.
So I will, you know, ask their opinion and leverage their intelligence and have them work together to think of ways where we can meet our objectives because the objectives affect us and that affects them.
So, you know, having honestly just given good communication and being good people and, you know, making sure they get paid on time and letting them know that we're here and we listen, you know, and that we listen to them and they listen to us.
And it's, it's, it's really nice that way because, you know, they don't have to and we don't have to, but we put our providers first.
And that is, you know, even things that tell Michelle are our VA like, look, we can, you know, say no to this corporate account, even though it's going to be a lot of money, but we really want to make sure that this provider is happy.
And, you know, if we can't accommodate this particular request, then we're just going to have to say no. And because the providers is more, more, you know, it's more important to us than that contract is.
Yeah, we, we really, we really took a lot of the things that we just didn't like about the corporate world and kind of traditional business.
And said that when, you know, when we did this, we were going to do it in a way that we could put our heads on the pillow at night and say, you know, we did our best and we were as helpful and transparent and nice.
As we could be while also making the best decisions that we can for the people that we're supporting because, you know, through the business that we started, you know, we have not only us, but, you know, these providers that have signed on with our service to take on jobs that we've, you know, created.
From clients. And so if, if we just have a lot of responsibility and we take it very seriously, because like, you know, we, we've seen providers that have started working with us.
You know, they, they, they're kind of, they come on there, they're like, they don't really trust that we're going to do what we say we're going to do.
Yeah, we have to prove it. And, you know, they come on having made $10 an hour, you know, no control over their own schedule, no control over what cleans they take really devalued and kind of like not sure if, if we're just making up stuff.
And so it takes time to get them to trust us and we value that trust and we value them.
You know, because without them, there would be no valley, the valley clean team.
It shows me.
Yeah, and to add to that, you know, we say upfront, we're not perfect and that's not an excuse for us to not be, try to be perfect and not be good people make good decisions.
But we also know they're not perfect. And so like robots, they're not real. He says this all the time, you know, when he's just even pitching to customers and you know, instead of today on the customer, he's like, we're going to make a mistake.
You know, we're going to provide you with the best clean that we possibly can. And we have very high standards for that.
But also, you know, you have a guarantee. I think there's a reason we have a guarantee.
Right. But I think it really comes down to just having some grace.
You know, like, hell, we, you know, we're going to mess up. And if we do mess up as owners of this company, like, we're going to sit down.
We're going to listen to the feedback. We're going to listen to line. You didn't like what we did.
How can we make this different? How can we make this better for you? You know, how do we miss that spot in the floor.
And it's 10,000 square feet. And then we miss it three nights in a row. How can we figure out what can we change process wise so it doesn't happen.
Yeah, because there's the ones there, you know, they're the ones physically seeing the space day in and day out, you know, and yeah.
I think just the honesty and just, you know, honesty, transparency and just being a kind about like, hey, we're going to, we're going to mess up.
Yeah. So we just work with them. Yeah. I mean, they don't work for us. We work with them. And, you know, it's just so far been very positive for us and them.
I like the way you put that that you they don't work for you. You guys work together.
I love to say that perfect doesn't exist. There's no such thing as perfect because with 8 billion people on the planet, everybody's vision of perfect is different.
So to have one encompassing word that will be and all be all it doesn't make sense. So as close as you can to the general perfect like you guys that said they're going to be mistakes.
Things happen, but we guarantee you, you're happy, you will be happy with the end result.
Yeah, absolutely. And, you know, just like everybody has a different opinion, what a deep clean is.
You know, it means different things to different people. But there's a reason that we have a checklist on our website that's also built in the book and call it.
So there's consistency. So consistency from the sale through, you know, through the walk to the door and explaining what the scope of work is to the end and the walkthrough and then the checking off of the checklist.
That's the same. So I mean, consistency is what built the business and what's going to continue to to grow it as well.
Kind of going back a little bit.
How are you handling work life balance and maintaining that that healthy relationship with it.
Yeah, I work eight to five generally every day.
And I'm in here, you know, looking at different markets and different ways we can scale and we're meeting our objectives or not.
And thinking of different ways to tweak them without, you know, the one staff would do have for a loop.
So for me, it's pretty much baked into if it's five o'clock. I'm done. And it's five or two. I'm light to go switch the dad mode, frankly.
So she's in the kitchen cooking and I'm going to look on the wall and see what the media is. And if it's, you know, fish tacos, I'm happy.
Or homemade pizza, pizza.
Oh, no.
And so for me, it's pretty easy. Like when we flexible to like like today, I didn't get started to work until nine because she had to get up and I had to get her daughter ready while she was getting her suffering.
So it's that flexibility of having somebody to to answer the phone. So, you know, for the first eight months, the business, I did everything, you know, and.
As we're going through different VAs and trying to find the right fit from a behavior perspective.
And so, you know, I was used to having to be here and kind of land a lot to the desk with phone calls, emails and text messages, you will from various platforms that we use.
And so for me, now that we have somebody that we truly trust who understands what we're doing and can always reach media slack or our teams or something.
You know, it frees me up to do what I need to do to help her, but also to switch gears and come back here and focus on the business.
Yeah. And I, those first, you know, several months of seven, eight months of, you know, I had to gently remind him that we have an answering machine, you know, answering machine, we have voicemail for the business for a reason.
He's always struggled with that. It doesn't matter if it's our business or somebody else. This is always struggling with an application.
So, you know, just leaning into the things that we've been trying to implement just in our own lives for better, just mental health and all of that and really making sure that we prioritize the things that we value.
And I am speaking, I'm singing to the choir like this is super hard for me to because, you know, he has to do the same for me, you know, we're, but like I said, we're both very driven people and we want things to succeed and we want, you know, we, we want to make sure that our clients, you know, aren't waiting too long to get a phone call back from us.
But also, I believe that if we are consistently unavailable after hours, if we're consistently setting those boundaries that our clients will respect that and that our providers respect that and they do.
And I kind of take the approach of again, we want quality, not necessarily quantity.
And so even on the client side of things like, you know, if a client is not respectful of our boundaries, you know, I don't necessarily know if this is going to work.
It'd be a good relationship for us because we do we are not, you know, I can count on one hand.
How many times players will come back from playing this is I never I don't want to go back there again.
Yeah.
And we respect that.
Okay.
Hey, tell me why.
And then B, you know, you don't have to, because it's your decision, you know, I appreciate you finishing the clean.
I'm glad it got done.
You know, tell me what, what happened, you know, and then we'll figure what to do our end, but you don't have to go back because no bad of that.
Yeah.
And because we want to identify the right clients for our providers, you know, we don't want to just send them.
On a cab call, you know, out to meeting, you know, claims they can possibly do in a day, like, no, no, I'll let you be over quantity.
Yeah.
Like you said, they're not robots.
You're not trying to stack it.
They have the APM.
Yeah.
We know with the.
Oh, I forgot to have lunch.
I'm going to do, I'm in somebody's shower.
I'm sorry.
What did you say?
No.
Not doing that.
The lunch.
And I think we, one of the things that we've learned is that we really have to look out for for our providers. I mean, no, they're not employees, but they're still humans and they're still helping us.
You know, get to where we want to go to. So, you know, we just.
We're in the boat together and so we all need to be.
You know, in the same, same way. So I got to make sure, Hey, hey, you're slowing down over there.
Could you be dehydrated?
Okay.
You know, did you say that's the most important lesson you guys have learned in the last year is just.
The understanding with the providers and being on the same page as a team.
Yeah.
Yeah. Honestly, because even if, you know, if we are on the same page, you know, and it's just about in this back communication, really, and, you know, truly, like Christmas and earlier, you know, that's really getting them to trust us, but earning their trust that we're not going to.
You know, like a lot of people that have worked, that worked with us now. They're like, Oh, well, I used to work for so and so and so and so and they only paid like 20% per job.
We do a 50 50 split and, you know, our providers get paid more than.
No.
You know, after all the thoughts come out.
And I'm okay with that.
I'm absolutely okay with that because, you know, they're, they're able to get home, take care of their family, go to soccer practice, go to basketball, one of the case may be cook dinner.
See her husband, you know, whatever.
Yeah.
Yeah. And, and, and, you know, have a good life. You know, I mean, I know how much they make, because I can see, you know, the connect account, I'm looking to all that how much went out of that person.
And I'm like, you're killing it. And I really do appreciate it.
It's a physically demanding job. It's not, it's not something that's, it's to be taken lightly.
I have a 850 square foot apartment with a dog and a cat.
And sometimes that takes me all data clean by myself, depending on how long I go between the cleans, but I can't imagine how efficient they are at a two 3000 square foot home by themselves if they are by them. So that's all day.
And then, and, and then getting pennies for that. It just, it doesn't, it doesn't make sense of, you know, part of our, you know, onboard onboarding.
Like when we're doing interviews, you know, something Kristen said, when we first started was like, look, we want you to do what you like, which, which you love to do.
But we want, we want to do all the boring stuff. We'll take care of, you know, making sure you get paid. If there's a problem, we'll make sure that that we address it.
You don't have to like have that confrontational conversation with the homeowner who is following you around Tony, which will, which rag to use because you're not doing it right.
You know, just step out, call the office and we'll take care of it.
You know, we found out very early because we were not, we've never been in the cleaning business. You know, I mean, we didn't have any experience with that kind of stuff.
And so, but just like every other job we were had, you know, you just learned the industry and kind of do it while you did it. But one of the things we did learn was that house cleaners house, you know, presidential cleaners.
They, they love to clean and they love the satisfaction they get after, you know, they walk into a very disarrayed home and they leave and the client is super happy.
And, you know, they bet that the toilet, you know, you couldn't even see it before. And now, you know, sparkling white, like they love that stuff.
But they hate confrontation with the client. They don't want to spend, you know, they don't miss. They don't like the marketing stuff. They don't like, you know, how much do I charge and how do I figure this out?
They're perfectly capable of capable. A lot of them have had their own, you know, business, you know, so a proprietorship and was trying to run a business.
They don't want to do any of that. I haven't talked to one cleaner who has come to us and said, yeah, I mean, that's, I mean, please, you know, let me figure out how to do taxes and make sure I get paid.
Yeah, so I take checks. Yeah, so kind of our pitch to them is we do all boring stuff. You know, we handle the marketing, they get in the clients, the client management, the schedule of the scheduling, they do not want to be scheduling everybody.
You know, like, that's just, they just want to do it. They just want to go in. They want to clean. They want to feel good after they leave.
Did they help somebody? Yeah.
Well, I John John and Jill. Yeah. Yeah.
We have one of our claims that doesn't pay a lot. And that's, and it's like, you know, it's, it's like a thousand square foot house, maybe smaller.
And the gentleman has dementia. And it was one of those things where like he was going to get kicked out of his house by like the health department, if he didn't have a claim.
Yeah, he couldn't come home. I think from like state, like the nursing home heart, the rehabilitation or something.
Like you can't say social services wouldn't allow you to be discharged.
Almost a quarter home.
It was just real dirty. There's lots of books. Okay.
The pest control came, got came out and then killed a bunch of stuff. And then we came in and get a quote.
And the control doesn't clean up. They just kill.
We're walking like, you know, we're doing like L's and Nebo's, Nebo's.
No word.
These are elbows like into like bed bug poop, you know, as we go across the floor and we didn't.
Sorry. Going back real quick. Yeah. I didn't know. Past control companies will kill, but not.
Yeah.
Pick it up.
Correct. So they spray or put bombs off or whatever and they leave.
They don't come back and vacuum up the dead bugs or the remnants of that.
I mean, I'm sure there are some that would like.
The local one here. Yes, but most do not. They don't.
They don't do that part. You know, they're, they're in the business. Kill a bug.
Yeah. And a lot of the claims we have where it's like, Oh, I've got roaches and it's like.
When they need to be dead first, you know,
Yeah. So it's, it's not like that. But, you know, our cleaners who call a claim that are like my,
they come back and say, you know, look, I, I know it's not a lot of money.
You know, it's like, you know, I'm 75 bucks or something, whatever it is.
And the, the, they'll say something like my heart is full for helping this man.
And that's, that's what really matters. And I think that's great.
And then it's great for me to recognize that, but also for them to recognize it.
And it's like, it doesn't matter.
And, and we tell them, again, transparency, we, you know, like, look, we're, this is kind of, you know,
this is not our normal claim. You know, this is something that this person needs,
leads help so that they can live in their home.
And it needs to be comfortable. It doesn't like people there. You know, he's,
who's by himself, et cetera, et cetera.
And I will say with our history, especially his, but also mine working in nursing home,
the nursing home industry, even though we weren't like daily in the, in the facilities and stuff.
We still, there's like a special kind of place in our heart for like the elderly and the people who need and the nurses and stuff like that,
but like the carers. So we kind of, it's a, we're kind of like parallel.
Yeah.
You know, because our providers actually help, you know, and, and, you know, I, I, we get calls all the time from, you know,
the, the husbands and the dads are like, please come help my wife.
Because we have four kids and she works a full-time job and I work a full-time job.
And we've got after school activities and we just can't get the laundry done.
And like, we can just do longer. Yeah. And we do. And, you know, and like, we just need some help, you know,
and it's like, absolutely. And it's like, we just need, you know, can you just come,
mop and sweep my floors, you know, like I can't get all the things done.
And I think that that's one of the things that, you know, as a mom and wife, like,
I lean heavily into this, like, I don't want to ask for help.
You know, I think I should be able to do all the things and do them to the top, to my standards.
Oh, you're precious.
But that's just not feasible, you know, and it's like, would you rather go to the soccer game and like,
I don't know.
It's been a time of your kids and your family or, or, you know, nieces and nephews or whatever.
And come home to a clean house. Like, it's okay to do that.
One thing I say, and I say it often, and maybe not often enough, it's like, you know,
money can't buy you happiness, but it can buy you time.
And, you know, it's just like, you know, we're coming to delegation earlier. It's the same thing.
Yeah, we have to.
You have to give yourself permission to do it. Yes.
And nothing, not feel bad about it, because you can't do everything to her point.
You're not a superhero.
Right.
And they can do it.
Because we both love Marvel that we discussed earlier.
We would love to be, but we can't.
And the difference between a good provider and a great provider in my eyes,
a good provider is going to come home, come into the home and do the job.
Great.
And, and, and leave the great providers going to come into that home and treat that home like their home and make it that like you said earlier.
Make the homeowner come back and tell them how much they warm their heart and they appreciate what they did and they treated their home like it was their own and just went above and beyond.
So those, those providers around the world.
Those are the ones that, that.
Take all of us happy as, as business owners, as, as clients for them. It's, it's.
It's not an easy job. My mom themed for, for years as well. So it's.
It's, it's simple.
When we go through our hiring checklist, but what do you listen for that's not, you know, a check box on a,
you know, form is, you know, do they have heart, right? Do they care?
So we, we search for that and all of our people that we're, that we're talking to and hire the right contractors and the right providers that they get it, you know, and they have it.
You want to, you want to have the business as, as cliche as overused as the big corporations have used this term, like a family.
You want it to truly be like your blood family, not okay. You did great. We'll give you a pizza party once a month and we're like family. No, not it's.
You will their car breaks down and they call you. It's all right. I'll come pick you up and I'll take you to the job or, or whatever needs to be done. That's.
Those are the things that go above and beyond and show as a business owner to the provider.
This company is, is here for you. It's not just another paycheck.
Yeah, right. I can think of a, I forget what happened, but one of our providers did something just above and beyond one of our clients. It was just amazing.
And they got a, you know, just a fantastic review out of it. So I think we gave, we bought them like crack over your gift cards because it was like, so I call it like the provider's husband and I was like, Hey, what's their favorite restaurant?
You know, and if you told me it's a lot, metal them and, you know, that kind of stuff and just.
And they were just over the moon, you know, because he didn't tell her, thank God, because I was just like, you know, keep us yourself. Don't tell her.
So the show with the mail over the thank you note and stuff like that. So just, just, we care.
That's amazing. Going more into your, your providers. How many office staff do you have? And then how many providers do you have?
Office staff, we have one.
Other than us.
And I'm trying to think how many we have.
I have to go look. So let me, let me pull it, look and fall over fast. I'll tell you.
And then going into the next question, where do you do your hiring?
Those are teams too. So 13 total providers.
Okay.
Those are teams.
So, right?
No, that was without the teams.
I didn't have teams.
And, and what are we, what are we doing? We provide, we find our providers on housekeeper.com.
On Facebook and a lot of Facebook groups.
And word of mouth word of mouth.
Sometimes they find us and then, you know, Michelle will direct them to our form that we have on our website, which links back to looking to all as a hiring section.
So we use one of those forms are to capture just general information about, you know, are they interested in, you know, working with us and this is kind of what you get.
Once again, it was, it was good, not, not perfect in terms of the form of creation. So we'll revisit that letter.
But, but yeah, so we find our providers that way, a lot of this word of mouth.
I'm always on the lookout for things to clean and people to do it.
So I've been loosed and I'm like, hey, I smell lemon.
Let's see. Okay, who's who's in the bathroom? And I'll literally walk up and say, Hey, you know, I'm just curious.
So he does, you know, employees or do you like a contract? And she's like, I'll work with so and so.
I'm like, well, good job.
You know, so I hand in my card, I'm like, oh, if you're interested in, you know, more and more, whatever. So I don't have any shame when it comes to that stuff.
I was like, you know, I'm a part of a business networking group called BNI and the BNI guys and girls that I work with.
You know, I'm teaching them to look for dirty stuff and also look for cleaners. You know, so not only do I'll, you know, try to pry ourselves into their businesses and stuff that they own.
But then, you know, I'm teaching them how to look out for, you know, for cleaners for us to hire.
When they're daily walk, but also look around, you know, that ceiling event and that restaurant is a place that I would not do that, you know, because it's covered in dust.
Like how bad.
And, you know, I know somebody else who has, you know, inroads with the general manager. So I'm like, Hey, let's talk about how we can help this person because they need it.
So I'm always, you know, he asks a lot of questions.
And that's not a bad thing at all. That's a very good thing. He's the extrovert of the relationship. I'm definitely more in my head and thinking about things and all that.
And it takes me a lot longer to kind of like, I have to be in like business mode to, you know, if I'm just out with our daughter and like, yeah, I just, I'm focusing on other things like what we're getting for, for dinner or whatever, you know.
But he is no matter where he is, what he's doing. He's, he's just, Hey, here's a, here's a problem. I mean, I'm a solution, you know, like you're out and you're like just saying how does somebody and like, you know, somebody's like, how are you?
And then the general answer is fine.
Go on.
Yeah, come on, do that.
I will tell them how it's really going.
So like Saturday morning, we had a carpet cleaning.
And somehow the, the person with the key didn't show up. So I had to figure that out.
And I'm all, you know, I'm sitting at Walmart and the guys like, Hey, how's your day? How's your morning going? I was like, well, personally, it's going fantastic. I said professionally, I'm going to figure out where to get this keeper.
And he was like, what do you do? So we got in the whole conversation of what I do and he's talking about.
How is staffing at the Walmart Tyrone Loop Center is awful. And so we had a whole conversation about what we do and, you know, how we, how we keep our providers happy.
And he was like, well, that's really cool. Man, I'm really glad I talked to you. And then I'm like, well, you know, have a good day and God bless you. And, you know, we'll talk about that too. So it's, I do it all the time.
No, you're not weird. It's just not something I'm super comfortable with. So, you know, but it.
It works, you know, because like he'll be in a waiting room somewhere and he'll be having that conversation and then he'll be getting up to leave and somebody will be like over on the other side of the room and they'll just be lying over and be like, Hey, I heard you talking about.
Or whatever. Like, do you do this or like my sister, she's a cleaner and, you know, like, do you have a car, you know, and like, so you just, you know, I'm a realtor.
I don't need help. I'm like, oh, okay. Well, yeah, realtor sounds great to me.
I'm a property manager and we have all the, like, how do you do apartment turnover?
And I'm like, yeah, absolutely. You know, so we'll schedule like like we could be there tomorrow.
Okay, great. You know, so I'm a little bit more behind the scenes.
I do a lot of like conversing in social media with like the mom's groups and like the local,
you know, area groups by sale kind of sell trade kind of those kind of groups and stuff like that.
It's just because that's just what works for me and my personality and also my time, you know,
so I'm not always having a kid with me. You know, you know, you know, we're moving and grieving,
you know, but and but that just works for me. So you don't just have to find out what works for
you and sometimes you do have to step outside your comfort zone, you know, and but yeah,
so we just try to play to our strength and go from there. So my wife says I have,
was a golden retriever energy. I'm, I could, I could talk to whoever. It doesn't matter. I will,
like, like you described Todd. Hey, you're at the store. Somebody else is having a conversation in
front of you. I'm not being nosy. I just hear it and yeah, and you're just going and talk to them
and in a two second thing that you say ends up in a 15 minute conversation. Well,
she's standing holding the bags, giving me the debts there. And I'm like, okay, time to go.
I'm like, I mean, yeah, yeah, I'm like, oh, well, I'm an explorer. I want more and a lady named Linda
is there didn't know her before then. And I'm like, did you find anything good? And she's like,
actually, I think I did. And I'm like, oh, what is it? You know, so we just started talking. And
then we ended up talking about what she works in nursing home. And we used to, you know, consult
for nursing homes. And that's a whole like, thankless job in itself. And, you know, there's a different
layer. But definite golden retriever energy for sure. Yeah. I like that. I like it.
They look opposite of, you know, I want to be like that. You know, it's different than the
hub drum energy over here. Oh, I don't know. You might, I might have to check in on later after
the interview. So you guys use the hiring portal in book and koala. How how streamlined has that help
with your hiring process? For us, it has helped us capture everything that is coming through. So
instead of like having no process, correctly, you know, whether it's the careers page, it's
built into our website, which links back to the form. Or, you know, when somebody calls the
office or sends an email to like info at, we can just work it to careers. And it, you know,
notifies us. I would say it's not completely streamlined. I could make it better where it's,
you know, attaching to a Google sheet or doing something else. But right now we just
use the basic functions of it and haven't done anything past that. But it has helped
to consolidate all the different inputs into one spot. And then I can like copy and paste that into
a Google sheet. And then from there, reach out and start scheduling, you know, tier one and tier
two interviews, depending if they passed your one. What is an automatic red flag on an application for
you? They don't have reliable transportation. Huge background check. Yeah.
What about before the background check? What if, you know, we ask them like,
you know, would you be able to, like, on the initial application, like, they don't have
a reliable transportation? That's the red flag. And, you know,
that's an automatic no, because you can't take a bus and you're not going to be Ubering,
because you're going to hang it or end of that. Because it's one of the questions we ask,
like, on the, on the form, it's like, do you want to make $25 to $55 an hour? If they say no, then
that's a problem. And then number two is, like, do you have a level of transportation? And also,
what zip code do you live in? So we capture where they live. So we can kind of get an idea
of what the radius is. So we have teams that live in certain areas. So we do cover, you know,
the entire swath of North Alabama and down the Coleman to get a lot of, like,
lake properties and stuff like that. But I don't want somebody who, I wouldn't want somebody who
lives, you know, an hour and a half away or two hours from a job to be like, I'll take that one.
And I'm like, probably not, you know, just because they want it. And that's fine, but it's
not conducive for them to, you know, to do it that way. So we want to know where they're at,
and that they're not like, you know, applying through a different platform that's like,
Oh, I live in Florida, you know, and I'd like to move for something, you know, so
other, other red flags only go through, like, the actual interview process would be, you know, if,
do they have any previous cleaning experience? So, you know, we, yeah, they don't, like,
it's not an automatic, no, because we do have teams and like, we are working to do kind of like
building, I don't have your career development, if you will, but like,
but that is something to kind of think about. Yeah, it's kind of hard to hire a contractor
does have experience in the job. Yeah, because it's just, you know, they just don't know what
they're getting into. Yeah, it's like, they happen to know what a deep clean is or a standard clean
is and like, and it has, we need to ask qualifying questions. So if they don't know the answer to
those things, I can't instruct them on what they mean. Yeah. So that those are things that kind of
knock out of potential applicants for us, just because we want to maintain the model that we have.
Somebody who's not in the industry would look at this and be like,
cleaning's cleaning. Yeah, I could help in there and do it, but if you would send that person into a
test clean, more than likely they're going to fail it. And it's not as simple as they think it is.
That's really not. And the answer I get a lot is like, oh, well, like, you know, I've
cleaned my house. And I'm like, well, that it isn't the same because you don't use a checklist
to clean their house and you aren't on a time constraint. Yeah. Yeah, we don't. Yeah, I mean,
we don't really care how long it takes. But like, the longer it takes, like, we can't take eight hours
to do a we're not somebody's house after five o'clock. Yeah, we have women. Yeah, we don't,
we're not in, like he said, we're not, we're not in a residential home. We want to give you
space back home from work and you want to take off your shoes. Right. We're very cognizant of,
like, for residential. Yeah, we don't schedule things after a certain time, you know, all our
new claims are in the morning, stuff like that. And also safety for our providers, something we
don't want. We don't say after dark, you know, in residential areas, you know, we do stuff at night,
corporate areas, so we just kind of have some boundaries for that stuff too. I'll look at
that word apparently today. I have said boundaries about a thousand. I thought you're going to say
quality all the time. We have quality boundaries. Everybody's got to have their boundaries and
they got to be respected. So we, you know, we make sure that, you know, and it's like, you know,
a lot of cleaners are like, oh, you know, I would love to take that four p.m. start job for a three
guys on square foot house and I'm like, no, you can't claim in the dark. You can't claim windows.
There's no sunlight because that regular light don't work, you know, and if you don't know that,
then we should talk more about that. You know what I'm saying is, you know,
and then you get all this stuff too. So we try to, you know, help them protect themselves,
just be by being good people, but also, you know, imparting knowledge that many things
didn't think about, such as you can't clean. You can't clean them dark. You can't clean them dark.
I mean, when you do, you messed up because light is, you know, sunlight's different than regular light.
Yeah, we have to educate our cons for that as well. Like, we think, oh, can you not just come,
like, I break it off. Or I get off work. I don't want somebody in my house without you
be without me being there. And I'm like, and like, what, what does it mean when, you know,
what should I expect? And, you know, all of that. So we just, we just try to make sure it's kind
of an educated educational thing for everybody. My sales face is very educational. Yeah, very
educational. All the time, I'm like, I'm going to teach you how we do it so you understand
what to expect the quality of, of, of, and how we're different than, than somebody else,
and how we see things through consistently from sale to execution to follow up.
You having the background and the, and the processes and all that is huge, because being a year in,
and, and again, going back, having the boundaries with the customers and the providers and knowing
that, where a lot of other business owners that are in this industry, at a year in, they're
still trying to figure that part out and knowing, should I do it? Should I not? But you,
you know, from the get go, this is how it is. And we're just going to
politely figure it out with you. It's not because you're still, it's still with your business. So you
treated you, you, you, your boundaries, you're pointing to like your contracts and stuff like,
I mean, and I've made mistakes, you know, when I'm still hoping to get paid forward, but I doubt I
will. You know, and it's like, hey, you know, there's a reason why there's a cash check option of
book and call, and there's a reason why we have integrations with other payment platforms, right?
And, and the reason is, is because you want to make sure you get paid, and you want to have
secure payment. And, you know, we very rarely take checks, but, you know, one of the things I would
tell, you know, business owners, and, you know, we had this brand new massive apartment complex,
and you look at the contract that you sit down and they're like, oh, well, you know, you need to
have a $5 million insurance policy, and you have to sign all this stuff where it's like,
if you have, and it's a general, like, it's a general building contractor agreement that
wants you to sign, and I'm like, no, I'm not responsible for your air filter or, or cleaning
off the screen on the back porch. So, I'm the, I'm the contract reader. You just gotta say no.
And I, I immediately, I'm like, nope. Yeah, I'm like, I don't care how much money this is.
We're not in this. And in every contract is negotiable. And if this contract is not negotiable,
they're not going to be good business partners. So, yeah, if you don't have the authority from
your property manager company to, like, take out this line item that doesn't even apply to us,
I'm not going to sign it and be held to it. So sure. So, I mean, nine out of ten times,
it's going to be a nightmare within the first 60 days anyway. So, right.
Whether it's flexible, then those are red flags for, for, for, for potential clients.
It's like, sure, you want the business, but is it really worth it?
Yeah, I would, we would rather spend time getting quality, the kind of, so we are very early on,
identify the kind of clientele that we wanted to work with. And that includes,
honestly, I have nothing to do with the size of the job or anything like that. It has to do with,
their personalities and what kind of, what they bring to the table, because we view
our clients as partners too. So, you know, it's not just about like, oh, well, this is a big job
and we're going to go do it, like, because so it's like, no, like we've had big jobs,
we've had small jobs and both can be equally not marriage. If you don't have, you know, the,
the right relationship and the set, the expectation, that is a huge one.
Like, you have got to set expectations with both the client and the providers, you know, so.
And then you had to deliver on that. Right. And the, and the, the provider has to know like,
hey, this is what we're selling. And so, like, if I want to,
if I want to take this job, then this is the kind of, you know,
this is the work order. This is what I say. So you got to make sure that, you know, it's,
it's part of the process. Follow process. Follow it. Stick to it.
If I said we're going to send you a text that says we're on our way when we're on our way
and you hit it when you get there. That's not part of that. We're going to make sure on the same page.
So there's a reason that technology exists. There's a reason why that was built.
And there's a reason why we do it. There's a reason why I talk about it because nobody else does that.
And, you know, from our competitor's perspective, and that makes us different and unique. So I used
to be like, we're not like the cable guy who you have to wait one to five hours on to get there and
show up. And maybe, because I don't think about it this way, but I say, you know,
everybody went on a plumber and then you took a half day off work and it turned into like a
whole day off work. I mean, how does that impact your business or like how your boss,
you know, looks at you or deals with you? That's frustrating. With us, you don't have more about
that because we're on our way literally when we're on our way so you can come let us say,
we can leave the key, you can do, you know, whatever. We set the appointment at 9am. So we're
we're going to be there at 9am. Like, you know, we're never, we don't have to guess. We don't have
any wiggle room on like, you know, like the the range for us. There is no range. It's right,
though, you know, I can think of one time we were late and it was like, you know, like a state funeral
or something, a better set was shut down. So other than that, that's what we're generally on time.
But we also have to make sure that our providers are clocking in, clocking out. The system doesn't
do anything weird. And, you know, so we can take a look at that for a recurring perspective and say,
okay, it took them an hour to have to claim this, or two hours first time, or, you know,
for this deep clean, what's it going to take to do it recurring, at least we can price the recurring,
you know, in going forward when we call it upsell. So, excellent. Are you always hiring or do you
only hire when you need to? We are always hiring, honestly. You know, there is there's jobs that we,
you know, have to turn down because we don't have enough providers in a particular area.
So, or maybe that one, the double coverage we have, you know, doesn't work or it's, you know,
a later job. So things like that come up where we can like, we have our primary and secondary,
but if you get down to the tertiary, you're just like this. So, we put it unassigned and then hope
somebody grabs it, but we also actively call and say, you know, hey, we've got this clean,
looks like if you're scheduling kind of work with them without bumping everybody else around and
making them aggravated. So, we want to do that. If those are all fit, you want to push it, right?
Yeah, and you know, it's okay to say no. Yeah, I'm so sorry we can't do it. Or we'll have like a
business owner friend who also owns a cleaning company like a Huntsville or something, you know,
and he'll say, you know, but somebody else says, it's a real good job is, you know, so and so. And,
you know, I'll call Justin to say, hey, here's a lead coming your way and, you know, I couldn't
service it, but if you can, great. Yeah, and one of the things too that we've kind of started is,
especially in our area, because we do service the whole North Alabama area. So, in the Scholes area,
you know, we don't have a lot of cleaners in this area. We don't have a lot of providers. So,
like one of the things that I've taken on is kind of like, I don't know, we don't even have an
official name for it other than just, you know, we're just training people to clean, you know.
So, like, I will, like, I have, I do, like, I like to do the commercial jobs and stuff like
after hours, like after Charlotte goes to sleep, I'll be like, hey, I'm going to go do this clean
or whatever. And honestly, it's like, it's nothing I ever thought I would be doing, but I took it on
as like, one of those things that was like, there's something that I need to help with this with our
company. And it's like, I don't know yet what that exactly is. And it turned out, it's teaching
people like, we can have providers. It's called OJT, you know. Yeah, on the job training, you know,
like, I'm kind of the team lead. And I, we, if we have somebody that we're like, you know, I really
think that they would be good. They just can't put them on a job on themselves right now. And it's
like, hey, if you're willing to work with me, you know, hey, let's, let's see if we can get you
kind of trained up and trained and give you the experience you need. And when the time comes,
and you can, you know, you can kind of take on your own jobs. And we've had some good success with
that. It's kind of all on the job training for us for me as well, because I'm not trained
other people before. So it's just a learning experience. We just want to try to identify where
the gaps are and what, you know, put our heads together and call them solved.
Yeah. So if you can't find cleaners that, that are ones that, you know, our own housekeeping.com
and don't respond to messages or whatever. Yeah, that's a red flag, you know, like, yeah,
how long does it take you to respond to this? How long does it take you to
find our email and accountable or not? You know, so we factor that into at least some of our,
you know, it's in my mind somewhere, anyway, in terms of just responsiveness. But, you know,
we do, you know, have our little training program. So we can bring people along that have the right
heart and just need the skills to give them the skills that they need to do the job right.
And they can, you know, do it under their own, you know, LLC or the case may be once we, you know,
what's the, what's the time comes to properly, you know, move them from training mode to,
hey, if you're interested in keeping doing this, this is what you can do and we can help you, you know, so.
Yeah, sure. Now the complete opposite side, marketing. What are you guys doing for marketing?
So, I mean, between the Google LSA and we've got some thumbtack that's been coming in
and he can speak a lot to the best. Yeah, but as far as like marketing campaigns or like social
media marketing, we really, it's really organic. And we purposefully didn't want to kind of
out jump our skis, you know, because it's like we are learning and we're learning the industry and
kind of like, what, what did we want our business to be? And so we just had to really be patient and
kind of like figure it out as we went. And so a lot of just hanging out, you know, on social
media, like I'm already in the mom group. I'm already in like our local like fossil trade groups
and stuff. And like, we have a local group and a lot of local groups are like, what's happening in,
you know, retail or whatever. I mean, they're, you know, and so I just kind of keep an eye out
for people looking for cleaners or cleaners posting like, hey, does anybody meet their house or
business clean or whatever? And then if it's, you know, looks to be something that, you know,
we need help in in that area or whatever, I'm like, hey, you know, if you want to, if you want
to talk more like go over to our website and, you know, or message us or you can, you know, pretty
much send a smoke signal and we'll, you know, we'll talk to you. And yeah, yeah, specifically like,
you know, but outside of the socials and some of the organic stuff she was mentioning, like the
B&I groups, very helpful. But we, we basically, I don't think we did this on purpose really
strategic wise, but it's like we make little influencers. So like the person who won the veteran's giveaway,
there was only like the person who won it. And we didn't do this on purpose. We didn't like, you
know, cherry picket, but it has been known to happen for marketing people to do that.
We don't do that. But it has for sure. So like the person who won it is, is like, hey, I'm going to,
you know, we're going to record the story. We're going to do this. We're going to get a picture
from the service record. And she's like, well, I'm going to go tell Ed that we won because I'm so
excited. And then secondly, I'm going to go tell everybody, and she's in like every social media
group and on every platform, you know, in our area. So I'm like, okay, win, win. This is great.
So not only is she happy, she has to tell people about it, and we still get to use, you know,
the content and everything else for our purposes. And so that's just kind of, you know, a happy
accident really in that case. But we are just constantly, you know, talking about our business
and making sure we have good traction across our, you know, our area, basically, that we operate in.
Whether it's through B&I or whatever the case may be, we're on Yelp and dumb tack and stuff like that.
So we're just maintaining a, let me use one of her words, I consistent brand presence.
Yeah. I feel like Facebook groups are very underutilized. It's free. And especially if you
live in the area that you are running your business, big help. If you're not and you're doing it
completely remote, it's tough because, you know, the group moderator might kick you out because
you're not living there. So they figure you're going to push services or something like that. But
stay within rules and, you know, don't be a dude in a mom's group. That would be bad.
I feel like a lot of business owners starting out, think they need a huge budget for everything,
massive website, all this, all this marketing budget, you could literally start 27 bucks.
Call it, call it 150 depending on how much registration is in your state for the business.
You could $27 for booking koala. You have your website there. You could set up Stripe,
collect your post in Facebook groups for free and do the cleanings yourself for a little while
until you hire somebody and you're rolling. Absolutely. And one of the things that like Cody
Sanchez talks about is like, look, you don't have to like have equipment. Like, for example,
like, let's say we're talking about pressure washing. You go on and advertise and, you know,
do your thing, set up everything for, you know, and you don't have to go buy a $5,000
power washer. You don't, and you say, okay, well, our booking method is 50% front, 50% when the
job is done. So when they book it, they, you know, to 50 50 split, you know, in terms of, you know,
down payment deposit, whatever, take a deposit, then go buy the pressure washer with those deposits
and then go do the job. Don't spend the capital you don't have.
Yeah. And my, my background in marketing, like, I was really into the, I was in business-to-business
marketing and we were really into, you know, filling up that funnel and all that, but you,
you can't, yeah, you have to sell something you don't have sometimes like to, you kind of have
to do both. So you make it kind of kind of, yeah, kind of. So it's, you know, and I, that kind of
is against my nature, right? So it's kind of had to lean into my training and, and say, well, I don't
have, I don't have this thing to sell. I don't have this widget to sell.
We're going to start washing mornings. We got to sell it in order to then make it to then do it,
you know, so it's, it's, it's a counterintuitive sometimes to some people and it is a little bit
risky feeling. But yeah, but if you've got like 20 awnings down Main Street that are dirty and
there's nobody else in town to clean them, guess what? You're going to figure out how to do soft
washing real fast. Real fast. Oh, yeah. And within a world, you have access, like,
effort is free. Okay. Effort is free. You've got access to most people have, you know, especially
if you're watching this podcast and interview or whatever, it's like, you've got the internet,
ask questions, talk to people, whether that's, you know, picking up the phone and calling them
or read, you know, and then, well, is it a scroll and tick tock on looking at funny videos, which I
do definitely support that. But like, you know, manage your time, you know, learn something, you
know, how, how do you run a business? How do you, how do you do that? How do you, how do you pressure
wash? How do you like, how do you clean? Like, how do you professionally clean? And you'll eventually
kind of make your own kind of list of things and how you like to do that and what works best for
you and your clients and, you know, that kind of thing, but you've got to learn it first, like,
jump off the cliff, you know, you hit the nail on the head that looking one thing I preach is,
how are you going to bring somebody else in to do something if you don't know yourself? I mean,
again, you can hire out. And if you have that time and money to hire somebody to get it done,
great. But when you're starting a business with zero to no capital and you want to move quickly,
the best way is learning and doing it yourself. Yeah. Until you can learn to go.
Yeah. For sure. So what's the.
What's the most successful marketing campaign you guys have had so far?
We really haven't run any campaigns, to be honest. We, like I said, we did not want to
grow too fast and we didn't want to have more clients that we could service and we didn't,
we wanted to make sure we had our ducks in a row, so to speak. So we've really just grown
organically. We are definitely in 2024 looking at this. We are definitely in 2024 looking to be more
more kind of structured in that area. But we wanted to make sure that we had our foundations
down first. You know, we, we didn't want to look like we didn't know what we were doing,
even though we sometimes don't know what we're doing. And so, yeah, we haven't run any.
The most successful campaign that I can think of was going to be the veterans one,
because it got the most reach. So the veteran and put together to attract people to submit
nominations in terms of interactions and, you know, impressions and things of that nature. That's
the most I wouldn't consider that a campaign. No, it was not a campaign. It was just.
So she's being very, I'm being very marketing.
We had an objective that we wanted to reach, and we put together something to reach that objective.
But I would not. Yeah, it wasn't. Yeah. Like the next thing is like we have our
year anniversary for our company. So it's like we're going to be giving away more
cleanings. And so we have certain things that are going to be structured for like current customers,
not just new customers, and then suffer people who aren't customers, you know. So we've done,
we've done both of those. We haven't publicized them yet. But, you know, we've,
you know, taken our first customer we ever had and said, hey, guess what? You get a free
month of cleaning on us. And would you please tell us how, you know, what kind of impact we've
made on your life in this past year that we've been cleaning for you if we have a minute in fact,
because her and I are friendly. And, you know, I call her and tell her, hey, we're going to be
coming to Marta, cleaned her house and she's like, oh, she would get, you know, so she gives
me crap. But, you know, it's fun. And she stuck with us. And, you know, that's the thing too,
is like, just be, and this is a little off subject. But be honest with your clients, you should be
like, Hey, we were like, we first started, we were like, Hey, you're our very first clean.
So if you don't mind, like, can you give us some really good feedback, like get their buy-in,
make them part of your success, you know, because they don't want to feel like a number. They don't
want to feel like, yeah, I'm just another got three Google reviews and hope you're good, you know,
yeah, like you're taking a chance on us. And so let us, let us help you help us. So
if hi, it worked. Okay, take a turn. That's, it's, that's huge. I, we posted something on the book
in Guala social media recently that was literally to, to that point is give back to your customers.
And, and once a month, maybe once every couple months, or you guys did it after one year in,
you went back to your first customer and work, here's, here's a month of cleans. You gave
back from reading your post. Yeah. Yeah, you gave back and it comes back into you guys. And it just,
it shows that you care for them. And it gives you, like you said, that insight into
how could we do better and how can, and thank you for sticking with us. Yep. Yes. I mean, I'm a,
I'm a huge proponent of, of, you know, building those, your own fan base, you know, like these
are the people who have stuck with you. How do you make your own writing fans? Yeah, exactly. So,
how do you get your own Alabama or Auburn fans? That good colors, uh, beer, hot dogs. A friendly
rivalry. A rivalry. That's a good one. Friendly. Friendly.
Sure. In the background, actually working together, just to drive a business to each other,
co-owned by some conglomerate you don't talk about.
Take it out loud. You mentioned networking earlier. Do you, how, how is networking playing
into your marketing efforts? It is. Um, I talk a lot. So it works out well. I couldn't tell.
I don't, I don't know. Yeah. It's huge. I mean, we are really, we really, yeah, we really just want
everybody to be successful, including ourselves. Like we, we are, we literally do not, we don't look
at like competitors in the way that like maybe people think you should. I, I don't, I don't look
at other businesses as somebody that, that do are in the same industry as us, as, as that like
competitiveness in the way that like, well, I, I don't want to be associated with you. If, you know,
it's like we would rather work all together in order to raise everybody up as opposed to
knock somebody else down in order for us to gain success. So, um, you know, between networking and,
and, and knowing, you know, who these people actually are and not just the name on the sign
out front or whatever. Um, that's really important to me. And then, and then he just likes to talk. So
he just helps animals. There's always a purpose. But there's the Goldman Retriever energy we're
going with. Yeah. I'm telling you, like when I, when I joined to be an I, you know, um, you know,
it was like, Hey, I think you'd be really good for this. And I'm like, okay, well, you know, and
it's helped with public speaking. It's helped with, you know, you know, developing a pitch. It's helped
with, um, you know, time management. And you know, I'm like the education coordinator for a group.
That's great. Um, you know, so I do a network education about like, uh, you know, leveraging
your time and leveraging, um, your, your systems and leveraging your energy and, you know, um,
there's nothing new under the sun. So I just take something I found and I tweak it and make it
better. So I don't usually create anything new from whole cloth. Not reinventing the wheel.
No, no, no. And you got to know your audience and you got to know, you know, who you're talking
to and who you're caught, who your customer base is. Like, because we, here, for instance,
because we cover the entire North Alabama area. Um, and the reason we do that is because there's
tons of people that live in the shows and drive our hour to 15 minutes to hunt still
Metro to work, um, every day. Um, there's people that live and grown up here and live in the Metro,
boss first, you know, so it's, it's just very integrated across North Alabama. And we're kind
of unique in that, I think. Like, I don't really know, like, what nowhere else that we've ever lived
is like that. I mean, even in Atlanta, we were very like, segregated in the suburbia versus the
city and all that kind of stuff. You live in the San Diego Springs. You didn't know anybody
live in Atlanta. Right. It just, you just, those were two different worlds. It's not like that
here. Um, it doesn't seem to be that way. Um, but it's all go and do the commercial stuff or,
you know, or, you know, go and do the commercial quotes. Um, go to other B and I meetings, you know,
use their, use their Facebook groups and stuff like that. We're networking. Um, but it's always good
to know what you're going to say. So my wife gave me pitch cards. I did. Yeah. But like,
messaging that works here in the shoals doesn't necessarily work in the Huntsville Metro. It's
they're just a different, they're very, it's, it's much, it's one of, it is the fastest growing,
or is it the fastest growing city in Alabama? I think it was just named like number one or
like best place to live by for like two years in a row for the world report. I mean,
so it's, it's a huge technology. You know, we've got the defense of, you know, defense. So there's a
lot of, um, growth growth in that area. And so there's a lot of people coming from out of the area,
um, into the Metro and all of that. And so there's just, you just have to know who you're talking to.
Yeah, they're not local generally speaking. They're transferred from like Colorado or, you know,
like that or, you know, whatever. And so those messages are, you know, hey, you're moving into
your new place. There's tons of, you know, new builds and construction growth that, you know,
all that kind of stuff over there. Over here, we're a little slower. We're a little small,
we are a lot smaller than Huntsville, but you know, it's just a different vibe, right? And so
you don't want to come at them in the same way that you would come at, you know, the people that live
in the Metro, you know, so it's just knowing your audience and knowing your, you want to do like,
you know, paid advertising through Facebook or Yelp or something like that, we would definitely
had different messaging for those areas. Yeah. It's like going into a local Facebook group,
you're not going to be putting what you would blast as like a sponsored post on Instagram or,
or a general Facebook ad. It's going to be more, I would say almost friendlier and kind of just
warmer, in a sense, to connect more with everybody's going through something. So like,
whenever somebody calls me and they're like, Todd, you know, you know, I'll call, I'll say,
thank you for calling the Valley Clinton. This is tough. You know, what can I get claimed for
you today? Something like that. And they want to know, all they want to know is how much it costs.
Well, I'm not going to tell you that in the first 10 seconds. So we can just hang that up.
But I want to know why you're calling me because there's a story. There's always a story. And if
you listen, you can hear more of the story. And you know, the biggest thing for me is just listening.
I know I talk a lot, but I do listen. Good sales able listen.
Absolutely. So in that respect, you know, whether it's I'm in town because my dad died
or having to get the house cleaned up the wake or whatever, you know, stuff like that,
or I'm moving, you know. So if you listen, you don't have to have repeat questions like,
now, what kind of claim do you need? I just said I was moving. So, you know, well, that sounds like
it'd be perfect for our ribbon move out, you know, cutting package. Let's go through that,
et cetera, et cetera. So if you're just starting out and you're not comfortable as everyone might be
on the phone, you might fumble that a little bit, which is fine. But just like you said,
listening and not getting ahead of yourself with with customers is going to go a very long way.
Going a little bit more into the revenue side of things. It's coming up on your first,
well, you just passed your first year. This is going to be your first full calendar year.
How much revenue have you guys done this year? Or you expected to close out?
Yeah, we're expected to close out probably 250,000 is our projection right now.
Wow, guys, that's fantastic. We're going to look at the booking
calendar before it's right below that. I know it projects to the end of the year,
but then wait, that doesn't include any new sales between now and then. So we're shooting for 250,
we're two plus now, I think. That's amazing. Congratulations. Because first year,
those are big numbers. That's huge. That's not. We don't really know. We're just,
you look at Facebook groups and whether it be the professional planners group or even the
booking calendar group, it's just like people are asking us what to questions and how to price
their services hourly and stuff like that, which those are things that we struggled with early on,
just to kick around. But we're just very blessed to be where we are.
And we're just thankful. Absolutely. Your background's helped, obviously,
but I feel like more than anything was the drive of your one year period of all the things that
we talked about in the beginning, that happened, your accident, your forced retirement, the birth
of your daughter, all those things added up, put that fire under you guys and it pushed you to be
like, we need to make this work as best as we can. And you guys took everything and executed it
perfectly. Besides revenue, of course, but revenue aside, what metrics do you guys really try and
hammer down and track? Yeah, so I do have, you know, being a super nerd who talks a lot,
we have a mix of metrics. We measure on our client satisfaction, obviously,
so our CSAT, our, you know, general NPS, we measure repeat business in terms of like,
can we take that one time clean? It belongs, it's not like a move out and they're moving out of
state or something strange and turn that into repeat business. So we look at that,
we have goals to grow our Google results from, you know, like 35 stars to 105 stars. So we're
focused on that. But how we do that, you know, I don't do hard as book. It's the four disciplines
of execution. I have. So they talk about like, you know, having a wildly important goal. So we have
one, two, three, four wildly important goals that we're focused on in different areas,
but they're basically expansion related. So we have deliverable accounts, work-class
customer service, skyblock growth, recruit the best cleaners, and then expand into two
additional cities, you know, within the next six months. So in that, there are certain KPIs
per measuring that will then lead to that. So those are the things that we've set from the,
from the top level, if you will, but then the rest of the team, whether it be marketing or,
or, you know, office staff, or even the cleaners themselves, can collaborate together on how to
take that top down push to measure the lead inputs they're doing every day, instead of measuring just
like, oh, what was already at the end of the month? What, it's already happened? You're looking at
lag measures, right? So we look at lead measures and lag measures in those areas to make sure that
we're, you know, reaching a good NPS score. We're reducing this client response rate in our,
you know, in our systems. So if somebody pays us on a Saturday, we don't get to it till Sunday
at noon. For example, how can we fix that? Okay, well, let's, instead of me getting the text message
and there's one too on a Saturday, well, there's a college football going on or something,
we'll, you know, institute bots or, you know, integrate to an AI or something. So they have a
response and can book and, you know, feed it data, you know, create a robust hiring strategy,
complete our quarterly engagement survey. So we have, making sure our people are engaged and
they're happy is like one of the big things, but then evaluate solutions for streamline hiring.
So like booking to all those, one of those, to streamline our hiring process more because it is
arduous because we do take a lot of time to do it. We don't just want to, you know,
suck in a bunch of resumes and spend a bunch of time, you know, that we've spent someplace else.
And some of it's like just, you know, documentation for, you know, how we're progressing on
VA's and, you know, making sure we have good FAQs and stuff to answer all our questions and
things that come up so we can, you know, be involved in the business and what I want to
give it a bear hug that day or if I want to, like, take a break and just set it over here and I can
understand it's working properly from the end of day report. So we measure quite a few different KPIs
and when we have the different lead measures that the teams come up with and we document
that push those up. So like if I want to get to a lot of reviews,
which are, you know, vastly important across local platforms, then how am I going to do that?
And I can tell them how to do it but it's, it's, it's really valuable to us that they figure it out
on their own and they, you know, have like an inception moment and they have accountability
between team members that they are achieving that and asking themselves, what is the number more
that I can do this week to grow our results in this group for this goal? So that's what we do.
It's not perfect, it won't be but it's, it's good and it's interesting to like it and it's,
you know, grown it from 28 reviews to 36 reviews in the last two weeks.
So, all right. I mean, like long as, like going back 1% better every day, you got those reviews
coming in in two weeks, it's, it's, it's big, it's momentum going forward and it just gives you
the drive to keep going and being like, all right, let's, let's we're getting closer to another,
another one is closer to that 100. Another one's going to be closer to that 100 and then once you
hit the 100, that's going to be 200 or 250 or whatever it may be at the next end to the next city
and start the process all over again. Yep. That's, that's, that's one of the operational
OKRs is like, expand them to additional cities. OK, well, that requires a lot of research and,
you know, I'm, I do that, you know, every day, you know, googling this and, you know, making phone
calls and asking what the pricing is on square footage and, you know, running that down and
seeing it to know a go or a go for that particular metro area, you know, so it's fun though. It's like
a game. Yeah. And then if I'm constantly, I mean, I'm aware obviously too of like our goals and
things of that nature, I don't do that micro day to day stuff, but I constantly have my eyes open,
you know, if I see a, you know, if I see a friend say something or text me a question that somehow
randomly relates to something that we're doing, you know, I ask more questions about
send him information. If I come across a news article, you know, that has to do with, you know,
growth in a particular city that we've been talking about expanding to like, hey, let's talk about
that, you know, like, so, you know, it's, they're building a new bridge is going to cut off this
section of town. How will that affect X, Y, and Z, you know, let's think about that. So, you know,
or the new, the team where she went to college is now a division one. They just got a $4 billion
investment to build X, Y, and Z, and then that's going to make this property value go up and work
can we go ahead and get ahead and, you know, you know, so stuff like that. So, so her and I have like
this, this good, you know, problem solving, you know, where we have a problem, we kind of attack
from all these different angles, you know, we're just see which one's the, the weak point, if you
will, to, you know, get into this, for example. And we look at things, you know, laterally, so
I'm a lateral thinker, so I'm looking at a problem. I'm looking like this right to left to see
what all it touches and how we can, you know, influence things to, to win, honestly. And,
you know, it would win for, win for us and win for everybody that we,
well, I don't care about it anyway. Never mind. Yeah, there's got to be a loser.
Yeah, if you're a loser. I think that earlier of, of keeping things separate with, with business
and personal life, got to, got to have the balance of this planning for financial planning,
you guys, you know, started the business because of a bunch of things snowballing
and a very short amount of time. With that impact, how do you go to now approach your financial
planning going forward with, with the business and, and everything in that sense?
Well, specifically, you know, we don't take a lot out of the company to pay ourselves with. We
have changed. It's interesting, you know, as soon as you get laid off from a job and you go from
like making, you know, a six figure income, mid six figures to zero in a day, that's kind of
a wicked call for, oh, well, you know, you make more money to spend money. So let's just change
our budget. So one of the things that we're doing from a financial management perspective
is, you know, we are living lean personally and professionally.
Um, what's that kind of thing? Remake? What's his last name?
It's a book called, uh, I can teach you to be rich. I can teach you to be rich. And it is about,
you know, and he's funny in the whole book too. So it's like, it's like some of the Dave Ramsey
principles, but not just rich. It's a, it's a, it's a psychology circuit, basically.
So it's not ramen and peanut butter and jelly sandwiches every day.
Yeah. Yeah. It's not that.
Rice and beans, right? Yeah. Rice and beans, yeah, yeah, yeah. So it's, it's, you know,
do the things you love, go back where you can and then, you know, it's like, for him,
it's like, I like to travel and have appetizers. So he just let them have lots of himself have
those things. He doesn't like, but it's like, Hey, do you need that PlayStation subscription?
Probably not. Yeah. Yeah. So we really,
I didn't even cut you on it. Uh, but yeah, we've really changed the way that,
yeah, we do everything. Uh, and then we, we cheer point, we, we plan, you know, future
forward looking, you know, and everything that we're doing business wise and financial wise. So
whether it's, you know, a lot of, um, you know, a lot of different buckets for the money sits and,
uh, you know, for future planning and, you know, taxes and all that kind of stuff, but I always
got to pay the tax, man. They're the first one coming with their hand out.
Oh, yes. So we, we, we, we, that's what we do. We just turn to this one and, um, in frugal.
And I guess that, that kind of answers my next question is strategies you use to manage your risk
is, is the same principles. Yeah. I mean, we don't have a horizontal basket, obviously. Um,
you know, um, we are, you know, from our growth pattern, we're looking, you know, not only this
business, but you know, we have other, you know, very good ideas and a hopper that, you know, we
can, uh, that are not cleaning related. So we like to, you know, diversify our income streams to,
you know, put it in a fun business way. But, um, in this particular business, um, we like to,
and stuff in something, Johnny O and, um, Johnny, Johnny and Sergio talked about,
it's like, Hey, you know, most traditional businesses will be like, Hey, I need to,
I'm doing real good. Let's put my money in marketing. No, capture everything down. You're doing,
have that playbook, which I'm looking at on this other screen right now, uh, in, you know, notion
or whatever you keep it. And, um, you know, rinse and repeat. Yeah. Don't reinvent the wheel. No,
I think the wheel you already have, it's working and just say, Hey, go to a different market. Yeah.
And then build the same thing you've done again. So as we get something coming along,
um, we're always looking at, you know, uh, scalability and, you know, our biggest risk is,
is honestly finding, you know, good people to do the work that have the heart, right? Um,
so I'm not worried about, you know, disposable income and, and, you know,
people not having, you know, services that they, you know, uh, they need and stuff like that. Um,
what our neck of the woods, um, we have set ourselves up to, to, to bypass that for the most part, um,
and go into sectors that are recession-proof or a gloss. Yeah, slow down on the recession. So,
yeah. I love that you guys don't go and, and get that success and then, and take the revenue and go,
well, I saw somebody posted in the booking wall community group that they're killing it with
this marketing strategy. So, oh, we got five extra grand. Let's, let's dump it in there because
depending on where you live, I've said it time and time again, all marketing strategies aren't
going to work the same in every single place. Yup, might work in Chicago, but it's not going to work
in, in Florida and an SEO. But nobody uses next door and all that. Right. Exactly.
So, you could have gotten that extra five or 10k in revenue and you lost it in two weeks by,
by reinventing the wheel and trying something new, whereas just do what you know. You've gotten to
this point already. You're successful. Keep doing what you're doing and don't, don't get ahead of
yourself. Don't try and outsmart yourself by being like, well, works for them. I'm going to do it.
You know what works for you. You got to this point by yourself or with, with strategy that
you've learned. So, keep on the path and, and don't deviate from that because you're just going to
derailleur your, your success. It's really, really hurt yourself if you, do that.
And one thing that we, we do is we, we take calculated risks. So, let's say we want to try a new
marketing strategy or whatever. We take a small portion of our entire marketing spin and we put
that aside to say, okay, well, when that random idea comes up or this new thing comes up, like,
here's a little bit of money that we already know is allotted for, yeah, like we already know that,
like, this is our fund money, you know, and so it's like, it could be as little as a hundred bucks,
but just depending on your overall scope of things. But like, you don't just dump everything into
the new thing. Like you, you keep doing what's working and you tweak that and you optimize that,
but then you take this little fun thing and be like, well, you know, if it go, if it doesn't go
well, then no big deal. We haven't also. We went into a realtor's association. No other
planning companies are the realtor's association at all. And as part of being an affiliate member
of the realtor's association, you get access to every lockbox that's very, very houses for sale.
So you guys walk in, there's no, hey, realtor, can you meet me at so-and-so's house to clean
it, dig already for pictures? So you are ahead of the game and you've already taken out like a
barrier, if you will, or an annoyance for the realtor to stop doing something else and making flyers.
Plus we get to go to their conferences and we have, you know, we sponsor new letters or whatever
it's going to be. But that gives us a leg up on our competitors because there's no other one doing it.
So then when we are in those meetings and they're all realtors and they have, you know, housing market
go boom, boom, you know, I can say, hey, you know, absolutely, we can go ahead and do that. And we already
have our own master key to every property that's on the MLS. And they're just like, oh, you do.
That's great. And that's not their money. It's their client's money. So it's sure even teachers say yes.
It was a small amount. We were saying that we were just like, well, if we don't get this on work,
then it's just something a couple hundred bucks or whatever. And they're like, that's really smart.
Do you only pay her to do that? I'm like, no, I don't want to pay her. Sorry. But I'll find one.
It's going back to what we were talking about with marketing. It's the channels that you might
just overlook because you're like, it's, it's not the main things. It's not pay to ads. It's not
SEO. It's not email marketing. But it can work if you just give it time and try it. And like you said,
it was a membership fee of a hundred bucks. Yeah, sure. What, what ad campaign is going to cost you
how much reach are you going to get for a hundred bucks? Little to nothing and you won't see,
you won't get any, any data out of that. Right. So you're measuring that reach with and like,
you know, you reach is, you know, it's subjective, right? So it's like, I want to know how many,
I, you know, how many actually close deals I got, I want them influencing from that particular,
you know, conversation I'm having with the chairman of that committee and how that's rippling
down in training sessions to their agents, you know, I mean, those people were being trained all
the time, all these sorts of CEUs they're doing. So, you know, anyway, where would you, what do you
guys see the business in the next five to 10 years? Where would you like to see it? We talked
this last night. So for five years, we would like to have, what we say, every, every, every
major metro that meets our criteria in the state of Alabama at a minimum. And then 10 years, we would
like to have the entire Southeast, you know, South Carolina, North Carolina, Georgia, Florida,
Alabama, Tennessee, Mississippi, Arkansas, maybe Louisiana, we can't that sometimes. LSU,
anyway. Yeah, so we would like to have all the major metros in those areas that mean our criteria
that, you know, that we're going into them and make sure they can support a business like ours,
make sure there's good healthy competition. I swear we can, you know, beat the pants off of them
politely. And, but, but, you know, really make a dent in people's lives and help them, you know,
see what a good quality, consistent, consistent quality claim might cause more than what you're
paying for, you know, the other people, but you get what you pay for. And there's a reason
quality and consistency. And, you know, if you get, for people to talk to, I mean,
love it. Going, going a little more towards the software side of it with book and go, specifically,
what role is, I mean, tech playing for your business, I know you have all these different
software, so it's somewhat, but how big is it for you guys to have that?
It's over 50% of what we do every day. So, booking, I have two main softwares that we, that we, you know,
that I open every day. One of them is Go High Level. And it's a particular version of that
called CleanWorks that we have. And then that one is booking, and booking, and takes care of
everything that I need. I can manage my cleaners. I can store their documents. I can collect
payments. I can make sure the splits are done. I can make sure that the refunds are done. I can
look at reports. I can do hiring. I can do emails, you know, all sorts of things out of that platform
that just makes everything a lot easier to deal with than having numerous systems that have to
talk to each other through Zapier or something. You know, you want to have one point of failure,
ideally, and then a backup. I haven't had any issues with booking koala, frankly, ever,
especially when it comes to like server load or lag or anything like that, that I noticed,
that are, you know, some traditional things happen. And the more you have, you know,
APIs and Zaps and stuff, the more things could go sideways on you. So it is a major part of our
business. I use it every day. And then the things that it doesn't do, whether design or maybe future
growth, we integrate that with CleanWorks. So like the text messages and phone calls, I'll come in
through that. And what I have a deal in, you know, or a quote or whatever, it communicates to that.
And then we'd go back and forth on, you know, making sure that most systems are updated to
who call back, who texted this, you know, or we closed or we opened, you know, all these
different systems and workflows and automations that make life a whole lot easier than it would be,
you know, even five years ago, you know, technology just grows massively every, every month, honestly.
I mean, I never thought I would be, you know, looking at chat and GTP bots or, or, you know,
some sort of AI platform is going to do sales calls. But it sounds like that this morning.
So I was just like, oh, why does that work? And what is that? So our tech stack is not too deep
because we try to keep it simple. And we don't want to spend a lot of money in
other places. But looking through all that is the main component of our business and without it,
we could function. And when you guys started the business, was it the first software you went
with or did you try something else and then you came to us? We looked at other things,
but it was the first one we went with. We looked at it at Java and I think home services or some
that was working a minute. How's it going for all? How's called for all? There you go.
But the simplicity of setting up booking koala and also the ability to have the business structure
that Johnny and Sergio gave us through HSA and just being able to say, hey, clone this and then
we'll tweak it, you know, made set up a breeze. And then, of course, a lot of the education and
learning that looking koala has built into its platform and the plethora of information that
is available. So if you don't know how to do something or if, you know, when the hardest part was like
integrating Stripe, and then that wasn't that hard anyway. So expediency was definitely the
name of the game when we started. It was like we had to have this done yesterday because of our
plants. And so we wanted to, but sure, we both looked, you know, we sat down and we went over
all the options and we've, I mean, it was very obvious to both of us just and that's based on
our experience. I mean, this is not the first software we've implemented. If I have to do it
our software evaluation, so we've done a few software evaluations. So we did have that in our
in our pockets, but yeah, it was pretty, pretty obvious, pretty quick. And honestly, you know,
when we're doing software evaluations, you're like, I used to run a tech company and it was like,
okay, well, let's look at health best software and, you know, let's manage all these other systems
and doesn't have, you know, remote management capabilities is a built-in, it's a free one about
antivirus, you know, all this kind of stuff. And you're generally dealing with somebody else's money,
but in this case, somebody looked at my money. So, you know, I'm like, okay, what's the best
bang for the buck and what's going to be, you know, easiest to get us off the ground that puts
his head in the shoulders above even people he was drunk. And that was looking cool. Yeah.
So what were some of the features that or what drew you into using it, would it be the the
experience that you had and the ease of kind of setting it up? And I use ease in your case,
because you have experience with other softwares. I know it's been tricky for others because there's
just it's very feature rich. And there's a lot of things that you can,
it's very customizable. You can run a cleaning service a hundred different ways. It's not cookie
cutter. And that's what we're tailored to is is how you want to run it. Yeah, you can.
So, yeah, for example, like we had partnerships with other cleaning companies that do different
things than what we do, like a steam cleaning service. A friend of mine started, he was like,
hey, I got an idea. I'm like, oh, you're right. So like, I could go in and let build a new, you know,
form, you know, I can sort of a new industry. So office cleaning, steam cleaning, you know,
home cleaning, whatever. And, you know, have it all on, you know, one booking page or separate
or whatever. That was massive for us to be able to like just adaptability adaptability. And, you know,
I'm in fact, a sort of photography business looks like a nice one too. So, there's that. But,
you know, the reports were great, the forms. I did the client benefit in terms of that. I love that
the building, the website, especially like we used a custom website, but have the booking page.
And then it could pull in the reviews that we got, you know, that were pushed out. So number one,
you have in system reviews. And then number two, you have it where they can like, you know, say,
hey, I want to do it to Yelp and Google and whatever else. So they could like one-stop shopping
instead of having to go to multiple platforms to talk about how great of a service you are.
They could do it all over for one spot. And the client for all this fantastic. They can go in
their reschedule stuff. If you set it up, they can cancel it. I don't do it that way. Because I want
to talk to them and find out why they're canceling it. If it's a true cancellation or just rescheduling
to be like, oh, I'm going to go vacation. And I'm like, okay, well, we're just going to postpone
that. And we're not going to cancel, cancel. And looking at that, you know, some of the coupons,
like there's a built-in like Facebook coupon on the booking page that, you know, gives us a code
and stuff like that. That's nice. The gift card is fantastic, where I can actually, like,
like the referral program, basically. So you can earn referral credits as you are spreading the word
about how great things are going. They get 50, you get 50, that kind of thing, which we still have
operational and how do people take advantage of that? The customers, the customer, your customers.
Yeah, my customers, yeah. So they'll log in and I'll say, by the way, we have a referral program.
So if you go into your portal, look up at the top, you know, it's just like, I think gift card,
things what it says. Give card, a few more to this right now. It's under, like, the login is
them to look at. But, you know, and they can, they can give, you know, a referral. And then
they earn credits, you know, and then how that structure works. And like, you know, it's not just
like free money. It's also, you know, be like, well, this happens after the other place booked
and done, you know. So we like that. I like the different views, especially, especially the map of
view of like all the booking, because we have different industries and locations and stuff.
So I can say like, okay, we have all these things this week are like one of our BAs. She doesn't
live in my state. She doesn't know anything about, you know, geographic Alabama, you know.
She had to Google an address and be like, okay, how else do I take to get from here to here? And
there's enough time for these claims and that kind of stuff, right? So that's helpful for her to get
a visual than just, rather than just a, you know, this is the job from the schedule.
Being able to like say the quote or have, you know, a draft is fantastic because I can like, okay,
well, her and I had a conversation. She's going to talk to her husband. I'm not ready to send her a
quote because I don't know where to her footage and, you know, her house is on Zellos, so I can't
guess based off of, you know, realtor.com or whatever. Another thing was the tracking for the
tracking for the providers. So like turn on the fact that I can track them from like when they,
you know, hit on the way or when they get there, they clock in, you know, how long it takes,
what the travel time is, you know, you can really lock down on, not necessarily if they're doing
anything funny, but just like, are they clicking on the way when they're on the way? Or are they
clicking on the way, sitting in the parking lot and then three minutes later, they clock in?
Because you can tell that from the stamps. But, you know, it's something you can dig into if you're
following the process or not, and it gives you the ability to do that. Also under bookings,
you know, looking at the checklist progress and the media. So the job media, I didn't realize this
because, you know, I'm busy. But looking at like an overview of like all the jobs in the media and
just being able to download everything to my Google Drive and then start looking for marketing
opportunities to use it before and after or stuff like that was massive instead of having to go
to every job. It'd be like, click, click, and the fact you can do video now. Fantastic.
Because we'll do videos and upload the video and then we'll go through the video like screenshot,
like certain things like on the phone and then send those as individual pictures for like we
cleaned the microwave. And it's faster to do the video and then crop it later or, you know, take
out the pictures later. At least the cleaner said that. Love to see. So I love all those pictures
frankly. Haven't used that on CSV yet. So let you know. The provider. All the provider app.
Chef's Kiss. Fantastic. Yeah. And I use it weekly because I do a clean weekly. And so I use the
provider app and I'm just like, this is fantastic. Like, you know, so it coming from like the marketing
side of things too is just like, I've looked at a lot of softwares in my time for like client
management and, you know, marketing, softwares and stuff like that. And just the cleanliness
of the design is great. The user usability of it. Just being able to see everything that you need
to see. But yeah, it's just very usability and just like, yeah, it's just it was almost like Apple
designed it. Like what they do it. Like what they design it with the end user in line and then
work backwards. You know, that's how I would take like that. So it is done to be efficient.
Very user friendly. Like there is it's intuitive. Yeah, I'm happy that has it because I don't
because I've had because I've used it when we go places and the cleaners use it. Obviously,
you know, when they and then when something happens and they're like, hey, clap me out, whatever I'm
like, I'm going to look at this and, you know, I can see what they're saying because I've had
the Apple my phone have like a test account as a cleaner. But then also, you know, I can look
on my end and be like, okay, well, it clocked you out for whatever. And, you know, let's reclock
you and evix it or whatever. So the ability to to have safety and controls is also great
from the admin side to see kind of what happened. And you can override things if you really want
to. So I like it. If you guys ever end up selling your cleaning company,
and you want to come be sales for us, that was that was that was chef's kiss. I got a say,
come on. I mean, I don't think I could have done better.
That's why I keep getting hired, I guess.
You're trying to knock out all my my my next question for sure. What's one feature that you can't
live with. One of the. All of them. One feature that you're got your eye on on the wish list on
that's up. I wish that I didn't have to have a second software and that you had basically the
communication platform for like inbound outbound texting and phone calls built into that into
your platform. So yeah, so I don't have to use clean works and y'all I can just use y'all.
So like they use, you know, Twilio and stuff like that. So as their phone provider, if you will,
so you can grab a number from them and stuff like that. Log all the calls, communicate back and forth,
you can, you know, I don't usually email any of your clients from that, although you can.
But yeah, I mean, it's it's basically fully a full one platform solution.
One throw can be great. Yeah. You know, it's as as an old software, old software, he'd come up,
he said that I used to work for a software company in Canada and it'd be like, hey, we're
spend, you know, our clients are spending, you know, so much of their other, basically, you know,
revenue resources on other things like, you know, phone systems or whatever. And it's like,
you know, he'd call it wallet share. So he'd like, you know, they have a dollar in our wallet.
We're only getting 10 cents. Yeah. But what if we get 70? Yeah.
You know, what what development cost and what acquisitions we have to make to do that or.
So, you know, it's fun to have an operational brain and also a sales brain, because it,
you know, you can look at things from multiple sides. But that wasn't one thing,
that would be the one thing for me, I would suggest is, you know, communication platform.
We will discuss that more. Absolutely.
My last number. Absolutely. My last two questions for you guys are more fun than anything else.
Nothing. First, are you guys happy? Just overall, in life, not business, not purse,
just is everything. Are you guys happy? Where were you at? Yes. We have had a lot of hard knocks
as we have mentioned and some we haven't mentioned. Yeah. I'll mention it now. So during all that,
like right if my daughter was born in 2021. Yeah. Like the next year, my father died, basically.
So sorry to hear that. So instead of saying it's fine, I'll say, you know, if he's in the
happy or he'd be with Jesus. So he is. And that's what I believe. But yes, we are, we are,
life throws a lot out you, social media throws a lot at you. You know, all the talking heads will
continue to talk. So we try our harness to cultivate gratitude and just be thankful and gracious
and not just at Thanksgiving. But every day when I'm like, ah, I can't believe that, you know,
we love to streak on that window or whatever. You know, that was something I was slacking
about earlier. It's like, I'm going to go back and play that big deal. But I'm grateful for that.
I'm grateful to have that other, you know, conversation I had with that client who is,
you know, very influential and I can make it right, you know. So there's no, there's good and bad
and everything from human terms. But I just, I'm grateful. Yeah. Yeah. We've been through a lot.
And, you know, we haven't always been happy. And I myself had, had many years of struggle with,
you know, mental health depression and things of that nature. And been through a lot. And
yeah, that cultivation of gratitude and just really focusing on your priorities and what you value
and like keeping those things in, in the forefront and keeping them in check,
has really, really gotten me and us through a lot of things. Yeah. And I think I'd very
kind of be a parent. That's fun too. You know, like mess my kid up by saying no, don't stick
your finger on that. I don't know. We'll find out because yeah. So yeah. But the one thing is,
you know, the flexibility, you know, it's not black and white thinking, you know,
many things can be true at the same time. And just knowing that like, even though things might
be hard, it doesn't necessarily mean it's, and we just try to like think for the pop. We don't want
to invalidate or are not value those experiences. Because we're all good. But like failure is the
greatest teacher. Thousand percent. Yeah. Absolutely. Because I have failed. So
I'm part of myself than anybody ever could be. Whether it be, you know, building an account
management program at a startup or, you know, building a cleaning company from that ground up
and hope that I'm doing it right and following, you know, the teachings and preachings of some
guys I don't know in California. It always gives you an, you know, scarcity and
failure give you an opportunity to pick yourself back up off the mat and to innovate.
And I innovate every day. So, you know, today was to innovate how to get chocolate milk.
Right. Yeah. For not, not for me.
This is not for me. So, final question. What advice would you both give to your 10-year-old
selves? Go ahead, honey. I'll let you stop with that because mine's going to be a dose reality.
My 10-year-old self, I would tell myself that you don't have to do all the things. You don't have
to do them all. And that's okay. For me, my 10-year-old self, I would say,
have fun while you can because grown-up life isn't always, isn't. You don't have it all
figured out. You're just older and still confused. Yeah. Or I'll live in for the first time.
Absolutely. Yeah. And, you know, yeah, that's what I would say. I mean, I can get into, you know,
other things, but the 10-year-olds, you don't want to care. I love those, both those ends. I love
this whole interview, guys. It was an absolute pleasure to hear your story and for you to share
with everybody everything that you've been through, everything that you're currently doing with your
successful, successful business one year in and you guys are absolutely killing it and just
doing it the way you want to do it, which is the right way because it's your way, you know. It's not,
you're not following somebody else the way they set it out before and sure you're getting tips and
ideas of how things can be done, but you're, as a partnership, you're doing it your way and you're
making it beautiful for yourselves and for your daughter as well. So I appreciate that.
You guys have taught me a lot. That's, that's the one thing that I come into these interviews
myself is so that I could always learn from the people that I speak with and I have truly
learned a lot from the both of you. So I do appreciate that so much.
Well, if you make more safe advice, I'm going to say something about what we're going to be.
We'll talk more of next. We'll we'll we'll.
Not a little. Yeah. Absolutely. We're not afraid to get into the hard conversations,
but we like to have fun. Everybody always has something going on. And then they talk about,
what does everybody say? So everybody talks about like, you know, they brag about like the
tattoo they have or the, they cut themselves, the kid or, you know, the scars of her body,
but don't talk with and love it. That helps us be more human because we all have stuff we're
dealing with. And if we can take some of that pain or, you know, energy and move that forward
to move ourselves forward and take us to go with us, then we will. And we are.
Absolutely. It's fun. I enjoy the same time.
Thank you. Thank you so much for your time again. It was an absolute pleasure and everybody else
take care as well. And until next week, every Monday, we drop a new episode.
So stay tuned and and watch out for that.